Let me tell you what "Like A Virgin" is about.
我告诉你们"宛如处女"在说什么
它是说喜欢大老二男人的女人
It's all about a girl who digs a guy with a big dick.
整首歌就是大老二的暗喻
The entire song is a metaphor for big dicks.
不是
No, it ain't.
它是有关容易受伤害的女孩
It's about a girl who's very vulnerable.
她被耍过了几次 後来遇到一个非常敏感的男人
She's been fucked over a few times and she meets a guy who's sensitive.
喔  暂停 把那些废话告诉观光客吧
Whoa. Timeout. Tell that bullshit to the tourists.
托比? 谁是托比?
Toby? Who the fuck is Toby?
"宛如处女" 不是敏感的女孩遇到好男人
"Like A Virgin" is not about some sensitive girl who meets a nice fella.
"真实的忧郁"才是  不用争辩
That's what "True Blue" is about. No argument about that.
Which one is "True Blue"?
哪一首是"真实的忧郁"?
It was a big-ass hit for Madonna.
你没听过"真实的忧郁"? 那是玛丹娜的畅销歌曲
I don't even follow that top-of-the-pops shit, and I've heard of "True Blue."
我不常听流行歌曲排行榜 但是我听过"真实的忧郁"
I didn't say I ain't heard of it. All I asked is, how's it go?
我哪有说没听过 我只是问歌怎么样
拜托别做玛丹娜的热情歌迷
Excuse me for not being the world's biggest Madonna fan.
我才不会　要玛丹娜
Personally, I can do without her.
我喜欢她早期的歌  "边境"
I used to like her early stuff, "Borderline"...
一唱"爸爸别说教"  我就关掉
but once she got off with that "Papa, Don't Preach" phase, I tuned out.
你们害我思绪无法集中
Hey, you guys are making me lose my train of thought here.
我在说一件事  是什么?
I was sayin' something. What was it?
- 托比  那个中国小妞  - 她姓什么?
- Oh, Toby's that little Chinese girl.- What was her last name?
那是什么?
What's that?
我在很久没穿的外套里面 找到的旧地址簿
It's an old address book I found in a coat I haven't worn in a coon's age.
- 是姓什么? - 我刚才在说什么?
- What was that name? - What the fuck was I talkin' about?
你说"真实的忧郁"是有关一个男人
You said "True Blue" was about a guy...
敏感的女孩遇到好男人
a sensitive girl who meets a nice guy...
"宛如处女"是大老二的隐喻
but "Like A Virgin" was a metaphor for big dicks.
我告诉你们"宛如处女"在说什么
Let me tell you what "Like A Virgin" is about.
它是说一个做爱机器的女人
It's all about this cooze who's a regular fuck machine.
我是说日夜不停地做
I'm talkin' morning, day, night, afternoon...
老二...
dick, dick, dick, dick, dick, dick, dick, dick, dick!
有多少老二?
How many "dicks" is that?
很多
A lot.
有一天  她遇到这个大老二混蛋
Then one day, she meets this John Holmes motherfucker.
他像《第三集中营》的查理士布朗逊
It's like, "Whoa, baby." He's like Charles Bronson in "The Great Escape."
她认真地玩他的老二
He's diggin' tunnels. Now she's gettin' serious dick action.
她产生很久没有的感觉 疼痛  疼痛
She's feelin' somethin' she ain't felt since forever: pain, pain.
朱? 朱托比?
Chew? Toby Chew?
疼痛  让她疼痛
It hurts. It hurts her.
不该痛的  因为她早就用过了
It shouldn't hurt her. Her pussy should be Bubble-Yum by now.
可是这小子操她居然会痛
But when this cat fucks her, it hurts.
痛得就像头一次做一样
It hurts just like it did the first time.
痛苦提醒"做爱机器" 过去做处女的感觉
You see, the pain is reminding a fuck machine...
what it was once like to be a virgin.
因此"宛如处女"
Hence, "Like A Virgin."
王
Wong.
- 把那鬼东西给我 - 你在做什么? 把簿子还我
-Give me that fuckin' thing. -What in hell do you think you're doin'?
我听烦了  乔 我们走的时候会还你
I'm sick of hearin' it, Joe. I'll give it back to you when we leave.
什么叫"走的时候"? 现在就还我
What do you mean, when we leave? Give me it back now!
刚才十五分钟  你老在念名字
For the past 15 minutes now, you've been droning on about names.
托比  托比
"Toby. Toby?
托比  王托比
Toby? Toby Wong.
王托比  王托比
Toby Wong? Toby Wong.
张托比  他妈的陈查理
Toby Chung fuckin' Charlie Chan."
我的左耳听玛丹娜的大老二
I've got Madonna's big dick comin' out of my left ear...
我的右耳听到托比日本  还有什么的
and Toby the Jap... I don't know what... comin' out of my right.
把那本簿子还给我
Give me that book.
你要收起来吗?
Are you gonna put it away?
我爱怎样随我
I'm gonna do whatever the fuck I want with it.
那恐怕我得留下了
Well, then I'm afraid I'm gonna have to keep it.
乔  要我开枪打死他吗?
Hey, Joe, want me to shoot this guy?
妈的
Shit.
在梦里杀我  你醒来最好道歉
You shoot me in a dream, you better wake up and apologize.
你们周末有听 K比利的"70年代老歌精选"吗?
You guys been listenin' to K-BILLY's "Super Sounds of the '70s" weekend?
有  棒极了
Yeah. That's fuckin' great.
听到他们播的歌没有?
You believe the songs they're playin'?
知道我前两天听到什么吗?
Know what I heard the other day?
狄法兰哥的"心跳是爱的节奏"
"Heartbeat, It's a Lovebeat" by little Tony DeFranco and the DeFranco family.
五年级以後我就没听过了
I haven't heard that song since I was in the fifth fuckin' grade.
我来的路上正在播 "乔治亚灯暗下来的那一夜"
When I was comin' down here, "The Night the Lights Went Out in Georgia" came on.
出名之後我就没听到过
I ain't heard that song since it was big.
出名时  我起码听了几百万遍
But when it was big, I must've heard it a million-trillion fuckin' times.
但这是我头一回知道...
But this is the first time I ever realized...
这首歌女主唱是杀死安迪的人
that the girl singin' the song is the one who shot Andy.
你不知道维琪劳伦斯杀死安迪?
You didn't know that Vickie Lawrence was the one who shot Andy?
我还以为是说谎的老婆杀的
I thought the cheatin' wife shot Andy.
人家在歌曲结尾有说
They say that at the end of the song.
我知道  混蛋  我刚才听到了
I know, motherfucker. I just heard it.
别骂我混蛋  除非你背出歌词
That's what I'm talkin' about.
我以前一定是没注意听漏了
I must've zoned out during that part before.
好吧  帐单我付
All right, I'll take care of the check.
你们付小费
You guys can get the tip.
每个人大概一块
Should be about a buck apiece.
你  等我回来  我要我的簿子
And you, when I come back I want my book.
抱歉  现在是我的了
Sorry. It's my book now.
我改变心意了 把这混蛋给毙了  好吗?
Hey, I changed my mind. Shoot this piece of shit, will ya?
好吧  每个人缴点钱给小姐们
All right, everybody cough up some green for the little lady.
快啊  丢一块钱
Come on, throw in a buck.
我不给小费
I don't tip.
你不给小费?
You don't tip?
不  我不相信这一套
I don't believe in it.
你不相信给小费?
You don't believe in tipping?
你知道这些小妞赚多少? 少得可怜
Do you know what these chicks make? They make shit.
如果她们钱赚不够  就辞职啊
If she don't make enough money, she can quit.
我认识的犹太人都不敢这么说
I don't even know a fuckin' Jew who'd have the balls to say that.
让我把事情搞清楚 你从来没给过小费?
Let me get this straight. You don't ever tip, huh?
我不会因约定成俗而给小费
I don't tip because society says I have to.
好  我会给值得给小费的人 他们使出全力  我会额外给钱
If they really put forth the effort, I'll give 'em somethin' extra.
但是自动给小费  真可笑
But this tipping automatically, it's for the birds.
我认为她们只是做份内的事
As far as I'm concerned, they're just doin' their job.
可是这些女孩人很好
This girl was nice.
She was okay. She wasn't anything special.
还可以啦  没什么特别的
What's special? Take you in the back and suck your dick?
何谓特别? 带你到後面去吹?
I'd go over 12% for that.
我赞成
I ordered coffee, all right?
我点了咖啡  对不对?
She's only filled my cup three times.
待这么久  她只给我续杯三次
I want it filled six times.
我喝咖啡要续杯六次
Six times? Well, what if she's too fuckin' busy?
六次  她要是太忙呢?
The words "too fuckin' busy" shouldn't be in a waitress's vocabulary.
女服务生字典里 不该有"太忙"这个字
Excuse me, Mr. Pink, but the last fuckin' thing you need's...another cup of coffee.
对不起  粉红先生 你最不需要的就是续杯
These ladies aren't starvin' to death. They make minimum wage.
老天  她们不会饿死 她们赚基本薪资
I used to work minimum wage, and when I did...
我以前也是  我不够走运
I wasn't lucky enough to have a job that society deemed tip-worthy.
还找到大家视为该给小费的事
You don't care they're countin' on your tips to live?
你不在乎她们指望你的小费过活?
You know what this is?
你知道这是什么吗?
The world's smallest violin, playin' just for the waitresses.
专为女服务生演奏的超小小提琴
You don't have any idea what you're talkin' about.
你根本不知道你在说什么
These people bust their ass. This is a hard job.
这些人卖命干活 这是很辛苦的工作
So's working at McDonald's, but you don't feel the need to tip them.
在麦当劳工作也很辛苦 可是你不觉得　要给小费吧
They're servin' you food, but society says...
为什么不? 他们给你上餐 但是社会说...
"Don't tip these guys over here, but tip these guys." That's bullshit.
"别给这些人小费  给这些人小费" 狗屁不通
Waitressing is the number-one occupation...
for female non-college graduates in this country.
女服务生是全国女性 学历不高者的优先选择
It's the one job basically any woman can get and make a living on.
任何女人都能靠这份工作维生
The reason is because of their tips.
原因就是小费
Fuck all that.
我才不吃这套
Jesus Christ!
天啊
I'm very sorry the government taxes their tips.
我很抱歉政府课徵小费的税
That's fucked up. That ain't my fault.
又不是我的错
It would appear that waitresses are one of the many groups...
the government fucks in the ass on a regular basis.
女服务生是政府恶整的团体之一
Show me a paper that says the government shouldn't do that, I'll sign it.
我会签名反对政府这么做
I'll vote for it. But what I won't do is play ball.
要投票决定  我会投赞成票 但我不会做跟屁虫
This non-college bullshit, I got two words for that: Learn to fuckin' type.
你说的学历不高  我只能说 去学打字吧
If you're expectin' me to help out with the rent, you're in for a big surprise.
甭想要我帮你付房租
He's convinced me. Give me my dollar back.
他说服我了  把我的钱还给我
Hey. Leave the dollars there.
别碰那些钱
All right, ramblers, let's get ramblin'.
好  扯蛋们  咱们去逛逛
Wait a minute. Who didn't throw in?
等一下  谁没拿钱出来?
Mr. Pink.
粉红先生
Mr. Pink?
粉红先生?
- Why not? - He don't tip.
- 为什么不? - 他不给小费
He don't tip?
他不给小费?
You don't tip?
"你不给小费"是什么意思?
- He don't believe in it. - Shut up.
- 他不相信这一套 - 闭嘴
What do you mean, you don't believe in it?
什么叫"你不相信这一套"?
Cough up a buck, you cheap bastard. I paid for your goddamn breakfast.
快拿一块出来  小子 你们的早餐是我请的
Since you bought breakfast, I'll put in. But normally I would never do this.
好  既然你付早餐  我出 不过通常我不这么做
Never mind what you normally would do.
我才不管你平常怎么做
Just cough in your goddamn buck like everybody else.
跟大家一样拿一块出来
Thank you.
谢谢
That was the Partridge Family's "Doesn't Somebody Want To Be Wanted?"...
帕崔吉家庭的"每个人都想被爱"
followed by Edison Lighthouse's...
"Love Grows Where My Rosemary Goes"...
接下来是"艾迪森灯塔"的歌 "爱在我的萝丝玛丽之处滋长"
as K-BILLY's "Super Sounds of the '70s" weekend...
继续收听K比利周末的 "70年代老歌精选"
just keeps on truckin'.
《霸道横行》
Oh, god...
天哪  操  老天
I'm gonna die.
我要死了
I'm gonna die!
不  我要死了  我要死了
撑著点  小伙子
Just hold on, buddy boy!
我快死了
I'm gonna die!
- 我很抱歉 - 把手给我
- I'm sorry! - Give me your hand.
我不敢相信她会杀我 谁会想得到呢?
I can't believe she killed me, man! Who'd have fuckin' thought that?
别再胡说了
Hey, just cancel that shit right now!
你受伤了  你伤得很重 可是你不会死
You're hurt. You're hurt real fuckin' bad, but you ain't dying!
这些血吓坏我了  赖利 我要死了  我知道
All this blood's scarin' the shit out of me, Larry! I'm gonna die! I know it!
抱歉  我不知道你有医科学位
Excuse me, I didn't realize you had a degree in medicine.
你是医生吗?
Are you a doctor?
请回答我  你是医生吗?
Answer me, please! Are you a doctor?
我不是  我不是
No, I'm not. I'm not.
那你承认你不知道你在说什么
So you admit you don't know what you're talkin' about.
要是你的业馀意见说完了
If you're through givin' me your amateur opinion...
向後躺  听著 我载你回会合的地方
...lie back and listen. I'm takin' you back to the rendezvous...
乔会给你找医生 医生会把你医好
...Joe's gonna get you a doctor, the doctor's gonna fix you up and...
你会没事的
...you're gonna be okay.
现在说  你会没事的
Now say it! You're gonna be okay!
说吧  你会没事的
Say it! You're gonna be okay!
说这句该死的话  你会没事的
Say the goddamn words! You're gonna be okay!
天啊
Oh, God!
说这句该死的话
Say the goddamn fuckin' words!
说啊
Say it!
没事  赖利
Okay, Larry.
对了  对了
Correct! Correct!
我没事
I'm okay.
看我们在哪里
Look where we are.
看我们在哪里  我们做到了
赖利  她有一个孩子 她有一个孩子
She had a baby, man. She had a baby!
我们在仓库里
We're in a warehouse.
谁是硬汉?
Who's a tough guy?
快说  谁是硬汉? 谁是硬汉? 你是  赖利
Come on, who's a tough guy? Who's a tough guy? You're a tough guy.
你是他妈的硬汉
You're a fuckin' tough guy.
好...我们在仓库里了
We're in a warehouse.
你看我们在哪里  我们到了 我们做到了
Look where we are. We made it. We made it.
我们做到了
We fuckin' made it.
我们他妈的做到了
We have fuckin' made it.
我们在仓库里 你看我们在哪里
We're in a warehouse. Look where we are.
你看我们在哪里  撑著  小子
Look where we are. Hold on.
撑著点...
Hold on.
妈的
Shit!
别再撞你的头了 你会在地板上撞破一个洞
Stop bangin' your head. You're gonna bang a fuckin' hole in the floor.
你不想把地板撞坏吧?
You don't wanna hurt the fuckin' floor, do you?
我无法为你做任何事 除非等乔到了
I can't do anything for you.
But when Joe gets here...
应该就快到了
which should be any time now...
他会救你  他会照顾你
he's gonna help you out, he's gonna take care of you.
好不好? 我们坐在这里等乔
We're gonna sit and wait for Joe.
我们在等谁?
Who are we waitin' for?
乔
Joe.
赖利  我很害怕
Larry, I'm fucking scared, man.
- 请你抱住我  好吗? - 好吧
- Would you please hold me? - Yeah, sure.
尽管害怕吧
You go ahead and be scared.
你这一天够勇敢的了
You've been brave enough for one day.
现在你放轻松  好吗?
I just want you to relax now, okay?
你不会死的  你会没事的 等乔来了  他会让你完全康复
You're not gonna fuckin' die. You're gonna be fine.
When Joe gets here, he'll make you 100% again.
我伤得很重吗  赖利?
Am I hurt? I'm hurt bad, Larry.
不算轻
It's not good, no.
赖利  你为我做的应该受到保佑
Hey, Larry...bless your heart for what you're tryin' to do.
我刚才是惊慌了一下
I was panicking for a minute back there.
但现在我恢复理智了
But I got my senses back now.
眼前的情况是我腹部中弹 不医治  我会死的
The situation is, I'm shot in the belly.
Without medical attention, I'm gonna die.
- 我不能带你去医院 - 去他妈的监狱
- I can't take you to a hospital. - Fuck jail, man!
你不用带我进去  只要载我到前门
You don't have to take me in. Just drive me up to the front, man.
丢在人行道上  我会照顾自己
Just drop me on the sidewalk. I'll take care of myself.
我不会说  我什么都不会说
I won't tell 'em anything, man. I won't tell 'em anything.
我向老天发誓
I swear to fucking God, man.
看我的眼睛  赖利  看我的眼睛
Just look in my eyes, Larry. Look in my eyes.
我什么都不会告诉他们的
I won't tell them anything.
你会安全的
You'll be safe, man.
你不会死的  好吗?
You're not gonna fuckin' die, kid. All right?
听我说  你会没事的
Listen to me. You're gonna be fine.
腹部是中弹最痛的地方 膝盖骨也是
Along with the kneecap...the gut is the most painful area a guy can get shot in.
不是盖的
No shit!
可是要很久才会死掉
But it takes a long time to die from it.
我说的是好几天
I'm talkin' days.
你会希望你死了
You're gonna wish you were dead,
但要好几天才会因伤口而死掉
but it takes days to die from your wound. Time is on your side.
这是陷阱  还是什么?
Was that a fucking setup, or what?
妈的  橘色被干掉了?
Shit. Orange got tagged?
枪伤
Gut shot.
操  棕色在哪里?
Fuck. Where's Brown?
死了
Dead.
他怎么死的?
How did he die?
你以为呢?
How the fuck do you think?
条子开枪打死的
The cops shot him.
- 很惨  - 这实在很惨
- This is bad. - This is so fucking bad.
严重吗?
Is it bad?
这样算好吗?
As opposed to good?
这下糗了  这下真糗大了
Man, this is fucked up. This is so fucked up.
有人在整我们
Somebody fucked us up big time, man.
你真的认为我们被设计了?
You really think we were set up?
你还怀疑?
Do you even doubt it, man?
我不是认为 我是真的认定被设计了
I don't think we got set up, I know it.
你以为条子哪里冒出来的?
Where did all those cops come from, huh?
前一分钟不在  突然间就蹦出来
One minute they're not there, and the next minute they're there.
我没有听到警笛
I didn't hear any sirens. The alarm went off, okay?
警报器确实响了 警报器响  有四分钟反应时间
When an alarm goes, you got a four-minute response time.
除非巡逻车碰巧在那条街
Unless a patrol car is cruising that street at that moment...
要四分钟条子才能回应
...you got four minutes before they can realistically respond.
才一分钟就有17个条子在场
In one minute, there were 17 blue boys out there...
全副武装  清楚他们在做什么
all knowing exactly what the fuck they were doing, and they were all there!
记得车里出现的第二批人吗? 那才是回应警报器的人
Remember that second wave that showed up in the cars? Those were the ones responding to the alarm,
但第一批早在场等我们了
but those first motherfuckers...they were there and they were waitin' for us.
你都没想过吗?
Haven't you fuckin' thought about this?
我还没机会想
I haven't had a chance to think.
我先只是试著逃离现场
First I was just tryin' to get the fuck outta there.
脱身後  我就一直在照顾他
And after we got away, I've just been dealin' with him.
最好开始想吧  因为我一直在想
Better start thinkin' about it, 'cause that's all I'm thinkin' about.
我本来不想来的  只想开车逃跑
I wasn't even gonna come here. I was just gonna drive off, man...
因为设计我们的人知道这地方 这边可能有条子在等我们
because whoever set us up knows about this place. There could've been cops here waitin'!
条子可能正在来的路上
There could be cops comin' right now!
我们到另一个房间 嘿  到那里面
Let's go in the other room. Hey. In there.
赖利  别离开我  我快死了
Larry, don't leave me.
我会在另一个房间  好吗? 我会在那边看著你
I'll be right in the other room, okay? I'll be right there lookin' at ya.
我会在那边看著你  好吗?
I'm right here lookin' at you, okay?
我在那边
I'm right over there.
赖利  我快死了  赖利
Larry... I'm gonna fucking die. Larry.
我在这里做什么?
What the fuck am I doin' here, man?
一开始我就觉得不对劲 一感觉到
I felt funny about this job right off. As soon as I felt...
我就该感谢完走人的
...it I should have said "No, thank you,"
可是我就是不听 每次买大麻被抓就是这样
...but I never listen. Every time I ever got fucked buying weed, the same thing.
我不信任他  觉得不对劲 可是我又想要相信
I didn't trust the guy, but I wanted to believe him.
如果他没说谎  真的是泰国货 那就太棒了  但从来不是
If he's not lying and it really is Thai stick, then it's great. But it never is,
我老是说打劫有这种感觉我就闪 可是我没有  没有  为了钱
and I always said that if I felt that about a job, I'd walk.
And I didn't. I didn't because of the fuckin' money!
做都做了  我要你冷静下来
What's done is done. I need you cool.
你冷静吗?
Are you cool?
好  我冷静
I'm cool.
在脸上洒一点水
Splash some water on your face.
休息一下
Take a breather.
放松  抽根烟
Relax. Have a cigarette.
我戒了
I quit.
- 好吧 - 怎么? 你有吗?
- All right. - Why, you got one?
好  研究一下事情的经过
Okay, let's go through what happened.
我们在现场  一切都很顺利
We're in the place, everything's going fine.
- 後来警报器启动 - 对
Then the alarm gets tripped.
我转身一票条子在外面
I turn around and all these cops are outside.
你说得对 这么一眨眼他们就蹦出来了
You're right. It was like, bam, I blinked my eyes and they're there.
大家开始抓狂
Everybody starts going ape-shit.
- 金发先生开始乱开枪杀人 - 不对
- Then Mr. Blonde starts to shoot all... - That's not correct.
有什么不对?
What's wrong with it?
好  警报器响後条子没出现
Okay. The cops did not show up after the alarm went off.
金发先生一开枪条子才出现
The cops didn't show up until after Mr. Blonde started shootin' everybody.
- 我一听到警报器就看到条子 - 不  我跟你说不会那么快
- Soon as I heard the alarm, I saw cops. - It wasn't that soon.
他们在金发抓狂後才现身的
They didn't let their presence be known until after Mr. Blonde became a madman.
不是说他们不在  他们确实在
I'm not sayin' they weren't there. I'm sayin' they were there.
但是没有在金发开枪前行动
But they didn't make a move until after Mr. Blonde started shootin' everybody.
所以我才知道我们被设计了
I mean, that's how I know we were set up.
- 拜托  白色先生  你看得出来... - 别再叫我白色先生...
- Mr. White, you can see that...  - Enough of this "Mr. White" shit.
等等...别说你的名字  我不想知道
Wait! Don't tell me you're fuckin' name! I don't wanna know it!
我也不会告诉你我的名字
Jesus Christ, I ain't gonna tell you mine.
你说得对  真糟糕
You're right. This is bad.
你怎么脱险的?
How did you get out?
我一路杀出来
I shot my way out.
大家开始开枪  我就杀了出来
Everybody started shootin', so I blasted my way out of there.
快点让开
Move it! Get outta the way!
让开啊
Get the fuck outta the way!
让开
快点  让开啊
Move it! Get outta the way!
天哪  你有什么问题?
Jesus Christ! What the fuck is your problem, man?
- 混帐东西 - 去你的
- You fuckin' asshole! - Fuck you!
让开
Move!
天
Jesus!
下车
Get outta the car! Get the fuck outta the car!
快让开
Move it! Move outta the way!
我干掉几个条子
I tagged a couple of cops.
你有没有杀人?
Did you kill anybody?
几个条子
A few cops.
- 有没有一般民众? - 只有条子
- No real people? - Just cops.
你能相信金发先生吗?
Could you believe Mr. Blonde?
那是我看过最疯狂的事
That was the most insane fuckin' thing I have ever seen.
乔为什么要雇用他那种人?
Why the fuck would Joe hire a guy like that?
我不想杀人
I don't want to kill anybody.
如果我要出门  你挡了我的路
If I gotta get out that door and you're standin' in my way...
无论如何  你得让开
...one way or the other you're gettin' outta my way.
这是我的看法
That's the way I look at it.
如果在关十年 和干掉一个愚蠢的混蛋之间做选择
The choice between doin' ten years and takin' out some stupid motherfucker...
这是别无选择的
ain't no choice at all.
但我也不是疯子
But I ain't no madman, either.
乔到底在想什么?
What the fuck was Joe thinkin'?
不能跟那种人合作嘛
You can't work with a guy like that.
我们很幸运没被他乱枪射中
We're awful goddamn lucky he didn't tag us when he shot the place up.
我差这么一点就毙了他
I came this close to takin' his ass out myself.
每个人都惊慌  每个人...
I mean, everybody panics. Everybody.
你会紧张
Things get tense.
这是人性  你会惊慌 不论是谁  就是无法自制
It's human nature. You panic. I don't care what your name is, you can't help it.
心里恐慌  在脑袋瓜里
Fuck, man, you panic on the inside, in your head, you know?
给自己几秒钟 掌握情况  面对它
You give yourself a couple of seconds, get ahold of it and deal with it.
可是不能乱开枪杀人
What you don't do is start shootin' up the place and start killin' people.
应该要有专业抢匪的样子
What you're supposed to do is act like a fuckin' professional.
神经病不专业
A psychopath ain't a professional.
不能跟神经病合作 不晓得那些变态鬼的下一步棋
You can't work with a psychopath. You don't know what those sick assholes are gonna do next.
天啊  你想那个黑人女孩几岁?
I mean, Jesus Christ, how old do you think that black girl was?
- 20岁? 也许21岁? - 如果有的话
- Twenty? Maybe 21? - If that.
你看到其他人怎么样了吗?
Did you see what happened to anybody else?
我和橘色跳上车  棕色躺下
Me and Orange jumped in the car, Brown floored it.
之後我不晓得出了什么事
After that, I don't know what went down.
之後是人人自保
It was every man for himself.
金发和蓝色  我不知道...
As far as Mr. Blonde and Mr. Blue are concerned, I ain't got the foggiest...
因为我一脱身就没回头看
'cause once I got out, I never looked back.
你认为怎么样?
What do you think?
我认为怎么样?
What do I think?
不是被条子抓到就是被干掉
The cops either caught 'em or killed 'em.
毫无杀出来的机会吗?
No chance they punched through? You found a hole.
对  那是他妈的奇迹
Yeah, and that was a fuckin' miracle.
就算他们逃走了  人在哪里呢?
But even if they did get away, then where the fuck are they?
你不认为其中一个可能带著钻石吗?
You don't think it's possible one of 'em got ahold of the diamonds and...
- 不  不可能 - 你怎么这么肯定?
- No, no way. - How can you be so sure?
钻石在我手上
I got the diamonds.
做得好  在哪里?
That's my boy. Where?
我藏起来了
I stashed 'em.
你想跟我走  现在就去拿
If you wanna come with me, let's go get 'em right now, this second.
因为待在这里只会陷入困境
'Cause I think stayin' here, man, we should have our fuckin' heads examined.
- 可是这是计划  在这里会合 - 那么大家在哪里呢?
- That was the plan. We meet here. - Then where the fuck is everybody?
一旦发现告密者  整个计划就无效
I say the plan becomes null and void once we found out we got a rat here.
我们不知道金发和蓝色怎么了
We ain't got the slightest idea what happened to Mr. Blonde or Mr. Blue.
他们俩可能死了  或是被捕
They could both be dead or maybe they're arrested.
条子可能正在局里拷问
The cops could have 'em right now at the station, sweatin' 'em down.
是  他们不知道我们的名字 但他们可能会提到这地方
They don't know our names, but they could be singin' about this place.
我发誓  我大概是在走霉运
I swear to God, I think I'm fuckin' jinxed.
什么?
What?
前两次打劫有四个人干
Two jobs back, it was a four-man job.
我们发现成员之一是卧底警察
We discovered one of the team was an undercover cop.
不是盖的?
No shit?
谢天谢地  我们及时发现
Thank God we discovered in time.
我们摆脱它  忘了整件事
We had to forget the whole thing,just walk the fuck away from it.
这次的告密者是谁?
So who's the rat this time?
蓝色先生?
Mr. Blue?
棕色先生
Mr. Brown?
乔?
Joe?
听著  这整件事是乔筹划的
Joe set this whole thing up.
- 也许他设计我们 - 不  我不相信
- Maybe he set it up to set it up. - I don't buy it.
我和乔是老交情
Me and Joe go back a long time.
我可以肯定告诉你  乔一无所知
I can tell you definitely, Joe didn't know a thing about this bullshit.
我从小就认识乔  好不好? 说他跟此事毫无关系是可笑的
I know Joe, and me sayin' he definitely had nothin' to do with it is ridiculous.
我能说我绝对没做 因为我知道自己做了什么
I can say I definitely didn't do it, 'cause I know what I did or didn't do.
别人我不敢说  因为我不知道
But I cannot definitely say that about anybody, 'cause I don't definitely know.
我知道你是告密者
For all I know, you're the rat.
我知道你才是告密者
For all I know, you're the fuckin' rat!
好  现在你用脑子了
All right, now you're usin' your fuckin' head.
我知道他就是告密者
For all we know, he's the rat.
他中枪人在垂死边缘
That kid in there is dying from a fuckin' bullet I saw him take
不准你骂他告密者
so don't you be calling him a rat!
听著  我是对的  有人是告密者
Look, I'm right, okay? Somebody's a fuckin' rat.
这鬼地方厕所在哪里? 我要撤尿
Where's the commode in this dungeon? I gotta take a squirt.
走廊左转上楼  然後右转
Go down the hall, make a left, go up the stairs and make a right.
- 对了  阿拉巴马怎么样? - 阿拉巴马?
- By the way, how's Alabama? - Alabama?
我一年半没看到巴马了
I haven't seen Bama in over a year and a half.
我还以为你们两个在一起
But I thought you two were a team.
有一阵子是
We were for a little while.
一起干了大概四票
Did about four jobs together,
後来就决定分手了
then decided to call it quits.
为什么?
Why?
男女的事搞太久就会烦
You push that woman-man thing too long and it gets to you after a while.
她现在做什么呢?
What's she doin' now?
她跟法兰克麦卡搞上了 他们一起干过几票
She hooked up with Frank McGar. They've done a couple jobs together.
了不起的女人  厉害的小偷
Hell of a woman. Good little thief.
解释一下电报的事
So explain the telegram.
五个人的活
Five-man job.
迅速地打劫一家钻石批发商
Bustin' in and bustin' out of a diamond wholesaler's.
之後你能把钻石脱手吗? 我不认识能脱手钻石的买家
Can you move the ice afterwards? I don't know nobody that can move ice.
没问题  我们有人在等著
No problem. We got guys waitin' for it.
史派维出什么事了?
What happened to Marcellus Spivey?
- 他不是一向都帮你销赃吗? - 不  他服刑20年  在苏山维尔
- Didn't he always move your ice? - He's doin' 20 years in Susanville.
20年? 老天  为什么?
Twenty years? Holy God. What for?
倒霉
Bad luck.
说得一点也没错
I guess you can say that again.
曝光的情形怎么样?
What's the exposure like?
顶多两分钟 不过是很棘手的两分钟
Two minutes, tops. But it's a tough two minutes.
光天化日  上班时间
Daylight, during business hours,
应付群众
dealing with a crowd.
但你会有人手应付群众
But you'll have the guys to deal with the crowd.
多少雇员?
How many employees?
20个左右  警卫松懈
I'd say around 20. Security pretty lax.
他们通常以盒子交易
They most usually just deal in boxes.
钻石工会运来未切割的宝石
You know, uncut stones from the diamond syndicate.
当天有一批以色列的磨光钻石
But on this day, they're getting a shipment of polished stones from lsrael.
这种店像铁路边的小站 隔天被挑走  送到佛蒙特
They're like a way station, you know? They get picked up and sent to Vermont.
送不走了
No, they're not.
可以分到多少  老爹?
What's the cut, poppa?
很丰厚  孩子  非常多
Juicy, junior. Real juicy.
听著  你想怎样随你
Look, man, you do what you want.
我要走了  我到旅馆住几天
I'm outta here, man. I'm gonna check into a motel for a few days.
避避风头  我会打电话给乔
You know, I'll lay low and I'll call Joe...
妈的  他死了?
Shit. Did he fuckin' die on us?
他死了  还是怎么了?
Huh? ls he dead or what?
- 他没死 - 怎么了?
- He ain't dead. - What is it?
只是昏过去而已
I think he's just passed out.
吓死我了  我以为他死定了
He scared the fuckin' shit outta me. I thought he was dead for sure.
不医治的话  他是死定了
Without medical attention, he will die for sure.
我们该怎么办? 不能带他去医院
What are we gonna do, man? We can't take him to the hospital.
不医治的话
Without medical attention,
他可能撑不过今晚
he might not live through the night.
他腹部中弹是我的错
The bullet in his belly is my fault.
你或许不在乎  但对我很重要
While that might not mean jack shit to you, it means a hell of a lot to me.
急事先办  好吗? 待在这里太笨了  我们得翘头
First things first, okay? Stayin' here's goofy. We gotta book up.
你建议怎么做? 去旅馆?
So what do you suggest we do? Go to a hotel?
我们有一个腹部中弹的人 不能走路  血流不止
We got a guy who's shot in the belly, who can't walk, bleeds like a stuck pig.
醒来後又痛得唉唉叫
And when he's awake, he screams in pain.
你有主意吗? 说出来
You got an idea, spit it out.
乔能帮忙  如果我们能跟乔联络
Joe could help. If we could get in touch with Joe,
乔可以带他去看医生
Joe could get him to a doctor.
乔可以找医生来看他
Joe could get a doctor to come to see him.
假设我们可以信任乔 我们怎么跟他联络?
Assuming we can trust Joe, how we gonna get in touch with him?
他应该来这里  可是他没来 留在这里让我神经紧张
He's supposed to be here, but he ain't, which makes me nervous about bein' here.
就算他靠得住 他对我们大概也不会太满意
Even if he is on the up and up, I don't think he's gonna be too happy with us.
他策划抢劫  却双手沾满血腥
He planned a robbery and he's got a bloodbath on his hands now.
有死警察  死强盗  死市民
He's got dead cops, dead robbers, dead civilians.
我怀疑他会同情我们的困境 换成是我...
I tend to doubt he's gonna have a lot of sympathy for our plight.
我会尽量跟这场混乱保持距离
If I was him, I'd put as much distance between me and this mess as possible.
你来之前  橘色要求我带他就医
Before you got here, Mr. Orange was askin' me to take him to a doctor,
送到医院去
to a hospital.
我不喜欢这个把他交给警方的主意
I don't like the idea of turnin' him over to the cops...
但不这么做  他会没命的
but if we don't, he's gonna die.
他哀求我要这么做
He begged me to do it.
好  那么我们带他去医院
Well, all right. Then I guess we take him to a hospital.
如果他那么说  我们就照做
If that's what he said, let's do it.
既然他不认识我们  这是他的决定
Since he don't know nothin' about us, I say it's his decision.
他对我略有所知
He knows a little about me.
什么?
What?
等等...你没告诉他名字吧?
Wait, wait. You didn't tell him your name, did you?
我告诉他名字  我从哪里来
I told him my first name and where I was from.
为什么?
Why?
前两天我告诉他我从哪里来 只是平常的谈话
I told him where I was from a few days ago.
It was just a natural conversation.
不该告诉他的  你干嘛要说?
What was tellin' him your name when you weren't supposed to?
他问嘛
He asked.
我们刚逃离警察  他中枪了
We had just gotten away from the cops. He just got shot.
他中枪是我的错
It was my fault he got shot.
他躺在血泊中  他在嘶吼
He's a fuckin' bloody mess. He's screamin'.
我发誓  当时我以为他死定了
I swear to God, I thought he was gonna die right then and there.
我想安慰他
I'm tryin' to comfort him,
叫他别担心  不会有事的 我会照顾他
telling him not to worry...everything's going to be okay, I'm gonna take care of him.
他问起我的名字
And he asked me what my name was.
这个人就快要死在我怀中 我他妈的该怎么办呢?
I mean, the man was dyin' in my arms. What the fuck was I supposed to do?
告诉他  我很抱歉 我不能给他这个讯息
Tell him I'm sorry? I can't give out that fuckin' information?
这违反游戏规则
It's against the rules?
我对你的信任还不够
I don't trust you enough?
也许应该  可是我做不下去
Maybe I should've, but I couldn't.
去你妈的  去他妈的乔
Fuck you! Fuck Joe!
我相信那是很美丽的景象...
I'm sure it was a beautiful scene.
- 别对我摆出施惠者的姿态 - 我有一个问题
- Don't fuckin' patronize me! - I have one question.
你有案底吗?
Do they have a sheet on you where you're from?
- 有 - 这下子好了
- Yeah! - That's that, then.
天哪  我本来担心可能性多大
I mean, I was worried about mug shot possibility as it was.
现在他知道你的名字、长相
He knows A, your name, B, your face, C, your hometown and D, your specialty.
你从哪里来  你的专长 警方不用给他一堆照片指证
They're not gonna have to show him a lot of pictures for him to pick you out!
你没告诉他任何缩小选择的事吧?
You didn't tell him anything else so they could narrow down the selection?
再叫你别罗唆根本是浪费唇舌
If I have to tell you again to back off, we're gonna go 'round and 'round.
我们不能带他去医院
We ain't takin' him to a hospital.
- 如果不  他会死 - 我很难过
- If we don't, he's gonna die. - And I'm very sad about that,
有些人走运  有些人则否
but some fellas are lucky and some ain't.
你碰我干嘛?
What the fuck are you touchin' me for, man?
你想搞我  是不是? 我让你看看你搞的是谁
I'll show you who you're fuckin' with!
你想开枪打我  王八蛋 来啊  开枪啊
You wanna shoot me, you piece of shit?
去你妈的  老白 这局面不是我造成的  我在处理
I didn't create this situation, I'm dealin' with it!
你的样子就像刚出道的小偷 我表现得像是专业强盗
You're actin' like a first-year thief! I'm actin' like a professional!
他们逮到他  就可能逮到你
If they get him, they could get you,
逮到你就更接近我  这样不行
they could get closer to me...and that can't happen!
你居然还瞪我  好像是我的错
You're lookin' at me like it's my fault?
我没告诉他名字  我从哪里来
I didn't tell him my name! I didn't tell him where I was from!
15分钟前你差点说出你的名字
Shit! Fifteen minutes ago you almost told me your name!
伙伴  你困在你惹的麻烦里
You're gonna get stuck in a situation you created!
你要是想瞪人  瞪镜子吧
So if you wanna throw bad looks around, throw 'em at a mirror!
小孩子不该玩得这么粗暴
You kids shouldn't play so rough.
有人要开始哭了
Somebody's gonna start cryin'.
金发先生
Mr. Blonde.
操  踢我
Shit. You're fuckin' kickin' me.
你怎么回事?
What happened to you?
我以为你死了
Figured you were dead.
你没事吧?
Hey, you okay?
你看到蓝色出什么事没有?
Did you see what happened to Blue?
我们不知道你和蓝色怎么样了 我们正在纳闷  说话啊
We didn't know what happened to you. That's what we were wonderin' about.
- 棕色死了  橘色腹部中弹 - 够了  够了
- Look, Brown is dead, Orange got it in the belly. - Enough! Enough!
你最好开始说话  混蛋
You better start talkin', asshole.
因为我们有事情要谈
'Cause we got shit we need to talk about.
我们已经吓坏了 不　要你这副神经兮兮的样子
We're already freaked out. We need you actin' freaky like we need a fuckin' bag on our hip.
好  我们谈吧
Okay, let's talk.
- 我们认为有告密者 - 我保证是有告密者
- We think we got a rat in the house. - I guarantee we got a rat in the house.
- 你们凭什么这么说? - 应该好笑吗?
- What makes you say that? - Is that supposed to be funny?
听著  我们认为这地方不安全
Look, we think this place ain't safe.
这里不安全了  我们要走 你应该跟我们走
This place ain't secure anymore. We're leavin' and you should go with us.
谁都不准离开
Nobody's goin' anywhere.
在这龟儿子身上撒泡尿
Piss on this fuckin' turd.
我们要走了
We're outta here.
别再向前一步  白色先生
Don't take another step, Mr. White.
我去你妈的  疯子
Fuck you, maniac!
惹上这种麻烦都是你害的
It's your fuckin' fault we're in this trouble!
这家伙有什么问题?
What's this guy's problem?
我有什么问题?
What's my problem?
对  我有问题  我问题大了
Yeah, I got a fuckin' problem! I got a big fuckin' problem...
乱开枪的疯子差点害我中弹
with any trigger-happy madman who almost gets me shot!
你在胡说什么?
What the fuck you talkin' about?
那一场枪林弹雨
That fucking shooting spree!
在店里  记得吗?
In the store! Remember?
去他妈的  他们启动警报器
Oh, fuck 'em. They set off the alarm.
他们活该倒霉
They deserve what they got.
你差点杀了我
You almost killed me!
混蛋
Asshole!
早知道你是这种货色 我绝不会同意跟你合作
If I knew what kind of guy you were, I never would've agreed to work with you.
你要吠一整天  小狗狗
Are you gonna bark all day, little doggie...
还是要咬人?
or are you gonna bite?
你说什么?
What was that?
对不起  我没听到
I'm sorry, I didn't catch it.
再说一遍  好吗?
Would you repeat it?
你要吠一整天  小狗狗
Are you gonna bark all day, little doggie...
还是要咬人?
or are you gonna bite?
老天  你们两个混蛋  冷静
You two assholes, calm the fuck down!
好了  放手
Hey, come on!
我们这里是游乐场吗? 我是唯一的专业强盗吗?
What, are we on a playground here? Am I the only professional?
你们的样子像一群黑鬼
You're actin' like a bunch of fuckin' niggers!
跟黑鬼合作过吗? 就像你们  老说要干掉对方
Ever work with niggers? Always sayin' they're gonna kill each other.
你自己也说过想把他干掉
You said yourself you thought about taking him out.
- 你说过那种话? - 我是说了  好  我有说
- You fuckin' said that? - Yeah, I did, okay?
但那是当时的事 现在他是我唯一完全信赖的人
But that was then. Right now, this guy is the only one I completely trust.
跟条子合作就像与虎谋皮一样
He's too homicidal to be with the cops.
- 你支持他? - 不  支持个屁  我们要团结
- You takin' his side? - Fuck sides, man! What we need here is solidarity!
有人拿热铁钳戳我 我要知道把手上是谁的名字
Somebody's stickin' a red-hot poker up our ass, and I want to know who.
操  听著  我知道我不是个混蛋
Fuck. Look, I know I'm no piece of shit.
我很确定你没问题
I'm pretty sure you're okay,
我肯定你是诚实的
and I'm fuckin' positive you're on the level.
我们设法搞清楚谁是坏人  好吗?
So let's try and figure out who the bad guy is, all right?
哇呜
Wow.
好刺激喔
That was really exciting.
你一定是李马文的影迷吧?
I bet you're a big Lee Marvin fan, aren't ya?
我也是  我喜欢那家伙
Yeah, me too. I love that guy.
我心跳好快  心脏病要发作了
My heart's beatin' so fast,I'm about to have a heart attack here.
外面有东西给你们看  跟我来
I got somethin' outside that I'd like to show you guys, so follow me.
跟你走? 去哪里?
Follow you? Where?
到我车子那里去
To my car.
干嘛? 忘了拿薯条配汽水?
Did you forget your French fries to go with the soda?
- 不是  我已经吃完了 - 是吗?
No, I had them already.
我有样你们可能想看的东西
I got somethin' I think you might wanna see, though.
- 什么? - 是大惊喜
- What? - It's a big surprise.
我肯定你们会喜欢的  来吧
I'm sure you'll like it. Come on.
我们还是得离开这里
We still gotta get outta here, you know.
不  我们要留下来等候
No. We're gonna stick around and we're gonna wait.
- 做什么? 等条子吗? - 不是  好人艾迪
- What for? The cops? - No. Nice Guy Eddie.
- 好人艾迪? - 对
Nice Guy Eddie?
你凭什么以为他没逃到国外?
What makes you think he isn't on a plane halfway to Costa Rica?
因为我跟他通过电话 他说他正在来的路上
Because I spoke to him on the phone and he said he's on the way down here.
你跟好人艾迪通过电话? 一开始怎么不说?
You talked to Nice Guy Eddie? Why didn't you say that in the first place?
- 因为你没问我 - 太好笑了
- 'Cause you never asked me. - Hardy-fuckin'-har.
- 他说什么? - 他说"留在原地"
- What'd he say? - He said stay put.
所以我先让你们看一样东西
So in the meantime...I'll show you guys somethin'.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
也许这条子能回答一些问题
Maybe our boy in blue here can answer some of these questions...
你们在说的告密的事
about this rat business you've been talkin' about.
你太猛了  朋友
You're a piece of work, my friend.
这主意不赖  把他弄出来
Let's get him the fuck outta here.
希德  你放轻松
Hey, Sid, will you relax?
我认识你很久了 我不担心  我知道你会还钱
I've known you a long time. I'm not worried. I know you'll pay me back.
别说我已经知道的事  别让我难堪
Don't tell me what I already know. Don't embarrass me.
你有几个月不顺利
So you had a few bad months.
你照别人的做法来 我不管是JP摩根或裁缝艾文
You do what everybody else does. I don't care if it's J.P. Morgan or lrving the tailor.out.
你会安然度过难关
You ride it.
维克韦嘉在外面
Vic Vega's outside.
- 等等  谁? - 维克韦嘉
- Hold on. Who? - Vic Vega.
叫他进来  我要挂了
Tell him to come in. I gotta go.
进来
Come on in.
我有个朋友在外面 别气馁  我再跟你聊  放心
A friend of mine's outside. I'll be talkin' to you. Don't worry.
欢迎回来  维克
Hey, welcome home, Vic.
自由的感觉怎么样?
How does freedom feel, huh?
是一种改变
It's a change.
那是悲哀的事实
Ain't that the sad truth.
坐  把外套脱了  别客气
Sit down, take your coat off, make yourself at home.
- 想喝点酒吗? - 好
- Have a little drink? - Yeah.
来一点人头马怎么样?
How about a little Remy Martin?
好啊
Sure.
你的假释警官是谁?
Who's your parole officer?
席摩史卡奈提
Seymour Scagnetti.
他怎么样?
How is he?
他是个王八蛋 连训练所都不让我离开
He's a fuckin' asshole.Won't even let me leave the halfway house.
这种事不断令我惊讶
It never ceases to amaze me.
为两毛五割老太太喉咙的黑人
A fuckin' jungle bunny goes out there, slits a woman's throat for 25 cents...
碰到好好先生做假释警官
he gets Doris Day for a parole officer.
你这种好人却碰到龟孙子
A good fella like you winds up with a ball-bustin' prick.
我很感激你寄到牢里的包裹
I want you to know I appreciate all the packages you sent me on the inside.
我该怎么做? 难道叫我忘了你吗?
What the hell was I supposed to do? Forget about you?
我要你知道那对我意义非凡
I just want you to know that it meant a lot to me.
那是我能尽的微薄心意
It was the least I could do.
真希望我能做得更多
I wish to hell I could've done a lot more.
多谢你  乔
Thanks a lot, Joe.
嘿  维克
Ah, Vic.
牙签维克
Toothpick Vic.
事情如何呢  小子
So tell me your story, kid.
你有什么计划?
What are your plans?
你这狗娘养的 看到你坐在这里  我不敢相信
You son of a bitch. I see you sittin' there, but I don't believe it.
- 你好吗  牙签? - 嘿  艾迪
- How you doin', Toothpick? - Hey, Eddie.
抱歉  我应该亲自去接你
Listen, I'm sorry. I should've picked you up myself.
我...操  这星期忙得要命
I was... My fuckin'...This week's been crazy.
老是在捅漏子
I've had my head up my ass the whole time.
你那么说真奇怪
Funny you say that,
因为你老爸正在说这件事
'cause that's what me and your daddy were talkin' about.
说我应该去接你?
That I should've picked you up?
不  说你愚蠢莽撞
No, that you had your head up your ass.
我一进门  他就说"维克  维克...
I walk in the door, he's like, "Vic, Vic...
...真高兴总算有人知道在做什么"
...I'm so glad somebody's finally here who knows what's goin' on.
"我儿子艾迪是一个草包"
My son Eddie's a fuck-up.
"他在搞坏生意"
He's ruining the business.
"我喜欢他  但是他不成材"
I mean, I love the guy, but he's flushin' everything down the toilet."
你那么说的  对吗  乔? 自己跟他说
That's what you said, right, Joe? Tell him yourself.
艾迪  听他这么说我替你愤恨
Eddie, I hate for you to hear it like this...
维克进来问我生意怎么样 不能跟刚出狱来访的人说谎
but Vic came in and asked me how business was.
You don't lie to a guy who's just done four years in the slammer.
说得很对
That's very true.
好了  别胡闹了  分开
All right, enough of this shit! Break it up!
快  这又不是游乐场
Come on, this ain't a playground!
你们想在地板上打滚 到艾迪办公室  别在我这里
You guys wanna roll around on the floor, you do it in Eddie's office, not mine.
- 爸  你看到没有? - 什么?
- Daddy, did you see that? - What?
这家伙把我压在地上想干我
The guy got me on the ground, he tried to fuck me.
- 你想得美 - 你变态狂  想在我爸办公室干我
- You wish. - You sick bastard, Vic.
You tried to fuck me in my father's office.
你想在自己家里私下做什么
Look, Vic, whatever you wanna do in the privacy of your own home...
就去做  不过别想操我
go to it, but don't try to fuck me.
我不认为你是那样的人
I don't think of you that way.
我很喜欢你  但你不是那种人
I like you a lot, buddy, but I don't think of you that way.
如果我是玻璃 我也不会把你丢到玻璃圈
Listen, if I was a butt cowboy, I wouldn't even throw you to the posse.
你不会的
No, you wouldn't.
你会把我留下自己使用
You'd keep me for yourself.
操了四年小混混 看到上等货色你会欣赏的
Four years fuckin' punks up the ass, you'd appreciate a piece of prime rib.
我可能会训练你  好人 可是我让你做我的"狗腿"
I might break you in, Nice Guy, but I'd make you my dog's bitch.
这不是很可悲吗  爸?
Ain't that a sad sight, Daddy?
入狱是白人  出狱说话像黑鬼
A man walks into prison a white man, walks out talkin' like a fuckin' nigger.
我想是 射到你屁眼里的黑人精子
You know what? I think it's all that black semen...
冲回脑内  又从嘴里冒出来
pumped up your asshole, now it's backed into your fuckin' brain...
and it's comin' out your mouth!
艾迪  你说话这么讨人厌 我会狠狠捶你了
Eddie, you keep talkin' like a bitch, I'm gonna slap you like a bitch.
来啊  好  闹够了  妈的  我受够了 你们两个都坐下来
Enough of that shit! I'm sick of it! Now both of you, sit down.
艾迪
Now, Eddie...
你进来时  我们正在谈正事
when you came in here, we were talkin' some serious business.
- 维克有假释的问题 - 你的假释警官是谁?
- Vic here's got a parole problem. - Who's your P.O.?
席摩史卡奈提
Seymour Scagnetti.
史卡奈提  操
Scagnetti. Fuck.
- 听说他是个王八蛋 - 他是个混蛋
- I hear he's a motherfucker. - Oh, he's a fucker.
除非找到工作  否则他不放人
Won't even let me leave the halfway house unless I get some shitty job.
你要回来替我们做事  对吗?
You're comin' back to work for us, right?
我想啊 但首先我得向这混蛋证明
Well, I wanna. But first I gotta prove to, uh, ass-head...
我能找到一份正常的工作 然後我才能自己行动
that I can get a regular, you know, job-type job before I can move out on my own.
我不能回来替你们做事
I can't come back to work for you guys if I gotta worry about, uh...
如果得担心每晚十点宵禁
makin' some silly-ass 10:00 curfew every fuckin' night.
好  这我们能解决吧  艾迪?
We can work this out, can't we, Eddie?
事情没那么糟糕 我们能给你找很多合法工作
This ain't all that bad. We can get you a lot of legitimate jobs.
我给你找长堤码头工人的工作
I'll get you down in Long Beach as a dockworker.
我不想搬木条箱  艾迪
I don't wanna lift no fuckin' crates, Eddie.
维克  你什么也不用搬
You ain't gonna lift shit.
你在那边根本不用干活
You don't even work there.
不过从记录上来看  你有做事
But as far as the records are concerned, you do.
我打电话给工头  说有新人
I call Matthews and tell him he's got a new guy, boom, you're on the rotation.
这样你就在轮班了  有打卡
You get a time card. It's clocked in and out for you every day.
你每天上下班 每个周末你　薪水
At the end of the week you get a nice paycheck. Dockworkers do very well.
码头工人薪水不错
You can move into a halfway decent place without Scagnetti goin'...
你能搬到像样的地方 史卡奈提不会问钱哪里来的
"Where the fuck's the money comin' from?"
他要是决定突然造访 就是我们派你去塔斯汀的日子
And, if he decides to make a surprise visit...
去接一批货回来
that's the day we sent you to Tustin to pick up a load of shit.
如果又来  抱歉  你错过了
If he comes back again, hey, "Sorry, Seymour. You just missed him...
五个小时前派他去塔夫特机场
We had to send him to the Taft airstrip five fuckin' hours away.
我们有一批货要他去接回来
We had a load of shit he had to pick up there and bring back here."
你不时要出差  妙就妙在这里
Part of your job is goin' different places. That's the beauty of it.
到处都有我们的地方
We got places all over the place.
维克  我告诉过你别担心吧?
See, Vic? Did I tell you not to worry?
维克本来在担心
Vic was worried.
我明天带你到长堤
I'll take you to Long Beach tomorrow.
让工头安顿你  我会跟他说明
We'll get you fixed up with Matthews, I'll tell him what's what.
我很感激你们所做的
You know, I really appreciate what you guys are doin'...
但我几时能回来做真正的事
but I'd like to know when I can come back...you know, do some real work.
很难说
Well, it's hard to say.
现在的时机很怪
It's kind of a strange time now.
情况有点...
Things are kind of...
情况有一点混乱
They're a little fucked up, is what they are.
我们要到赌城开一个重要的会
We're just gettin' ready for a big meetin' right now in Vegas.
先让艾迪招呼你到长堤住下
Look, just let Eddie for now set you up at Long Beach.
给你找份差事  给你一些钱 让这个史卡奈提别来烦你
Get you a job, give you some cash...
and get this Scagnetti fuck off your back...
然後我们再跟你谈  好吗?
and then we'll talk to you, all right?
- 爸  我有一个想法  - 听我说完
- Dad, I got an idea. - Just hear me out.
我知道你不喜欢用手下抢劫
I know you don't like usin' the boys on these jobs...
但维克一向给我们带来好运
but Vic here...I mean, he's only been nothin' but good luck for us.
他是幸运符  拜托
The guy's a fuckin' rabbit's foot, for cryin' out loud.
我想让他参一脚
I'd like to have him in.
你知道他能照顾自己又可靠
You know he can handle himself, and you damn sure know you can trust him.
好  维克  你是否想...
All right, Vic...how would you feel about...
跟另外五个人干一票吗?
pullin' a job with about five other guys?
我太想了
I'd feel great about it.
K比利"70年代老歌精选"继续
K-BILLY's "Super Sounds of the '70s" continues.
如果你是第12位来电者 你将赢到两张今晚卡森游乐场
If you're the 12th caller...
you'll win two tickets to the monster truck extravaganza...
怪兽列车盛会的入场券 包括有"大爹地唐波汀"的巨兽卡车
being held tonight at the Carson Fairgrounds...
featuring Big Daddy Don Bodine's truck, "The Behemoth."
第12位来电者赢得本电台大奖
The 12th caller wins on the station where the '70s survived.
戴夫  这边事情大条了
Hey, Dov, we got a major situation here.
我知道你知道了 我要跟爸说话  看他怎么处理
I know you know that. I gotta talk to Daddy and find out what he wants done.
我只知道维克告诉我 说那地方变成黄蜂巢
All I know is what Vic told me. The place turned into a bullet-fest.
他抓了一个条子做人质逃逸
He took a cop hostage just to get the fuck outta there.
起来! 起来!
Get up! Get up!
我的语气像在说笑吗?
Do I sound like I'm fuckin' jokin'?
他在後车箱载一个条子乱逛
He's fuckin' drivin' around with a cop in his trunk!
我不知道谁做了什么 我不知道赃物在谁手上
I don't know who did what! I don't know who's got the loot.
我不知道有没有人拿到赃物 我不知道谁死谁生
I don't know if anybody's got the loot.
我不知道谁被抓  谁没被抓
I don't know who's dead, who's alive, who's caught, who's not.
我会知道的  我快到了
I will know. I'm practically there now.
我要跟这些人怎么说到爸?
But what do I tell these guys about Daddy?
好  你确定他那么说吗?
All right. You sure that's what he said?
好  我也是那么想
Okay, that's what I'll tell 'em.
去你妈的  你想当英雄吗?
Huh? Fuck you! You like bein' a fuckin' hero?
你想当他妈的英雄吗? 操
You like bein' a fuckin' hero? You like bein' a fuckin' hero?
你会受苦  血淋淋的  朋友
You're gonna suffer for nothin', pal.
听到没? 你会招的  不然...
You hear me? 'Cause you're gonna fuckin' talk.
- 我什么都不知道 - 你他妈的知道
- I don't fucking know anything! - You fuckin' know.
你知道  看著我 你他妈的知道
You know. Look at me. You fuckin' know.
这里是怎么回事?
What in the Sam Hill's goin' on here?
好人  我们抓到一个条子  - 乔在哪?
- Nice Guy, we got a cop. - Where the fuck is Joe?
- 妈的  橘色死了 - 不  他没死
- Holy shit. Orange is dead. - No, he's not dead,
但如果不医他  他会死的
but he will be if we don't get him taken care of.
我们被设计了 条子在现场等我们
We were set up. The cops were there waitin' for us.
什么? 没有人设计任何人
What? Nobody fuckin' set anybody up.
- 警察在那边等我们 - 胡说
- The cops were there waitin' for us. - Bullshit.
去你的  你又不在场
Fuck you, man! You weren't there,
我们在 我告诉你  警察在监视那家店
we were, and the cops had that store staked out.
好  侦探先生  你他妈的聪明 是谁干的?
Okay, Mr. Fuckin' Detective, you're so fuckin' smart. Who did it?
你以为我们在问对方什么?
We've been askin' each other!
是吗? 有什么结论了?
What'd you come up with?
你们以为是我设计你们?
You think I fuckin' set you up?
我不晓得  有人就是了
I don't know, but somebody did.
没有人会干
Nobody did.
你们这些混蛋把珠宝店变成...
You fuckin' assholes turned the jewelry store...
别骂我混蛋
Don't you call me an asshole!
狂野西部秀  白痴
You fuckin' idiot!
把珠宝店变成狂野西部秀
Turned the jewelry store into a wild west show...
- 你别骂我白痴 - 居然还纳闷条子怎么会出现
and you wonder why the fuckin' cops show up?
乔在哪里?
Where's Joseph?
我不知道  我还没跟他谈过
I don't know. I ain't talked to him.
我跟戴夫通过电话 他说爸要过来  他很火大
I talked to Dov. He says Daddy's comin' down here and he's fuckin' pissed.
他很火大? 跟你说过他会火大吧
He's pissed? I told you he'd be pissed.
- 乔说了什么? - 我说了  我还没跟他谈过
- What'd Joe say? - I told you, I ain't talked to him!
- 我只知道他很火大 - 我们要怎么处理他?
- All I know is he's pissed. - What are you gonna do about him?
老天  给我个喘息的机会 我自己也有一些问题
Give me a fuckin' chance to breathe. I got a few questions of my own here.
又不是你要死  是他
You ain't dying. He is.
好  同情先生  我会打电话找人
All right, Mr. Fuckin' Compassion, I will call somebody!
- 谁? - 他妈的玩蛇人
- Who? - A fuckin' snake charmer!
你以为呢? 我会打电话找医生 他会把他医好
Who do you think? I'll call a doctor. They'll fix him right up.
棕色和蓝色出了什么事?
What happened to Brown and Blue?
棕色死了  蓝色不知道怎么样
Brown's dead. We don't know what happened to Blue.
棕色死了?
Brown's dead?
- 你确定吗? - 我确定  我在场
- Are you sure? - I'm sure. I was there.
他头部中了一枪
He took one in the head.
没有人知道蓝色怎么样吗?
Nobody's got a clue what happened to Mr. Blue?
他不是活命  就是死了
Either he's alive or he's dead...
要不就是警察抓了他
or the cops got him
要不就是没抓到
or they don't.
这八成就是你提到的那个畜牲 你们为什么揍他?
I take it this is the bastard you told me about. Why are you beatin' on him?
他也许能说出是谁设计我们
Maybe he could tell us who set us up.
你们要是痛打这个混蛋 他会说芝加哥大火是他放的
You beat this prick long enough, he'll tell you he started the Chicago Fire.
那又不一定会是真的
Now that don't necessarily make it fuckin' so!
拜托  想一想
Come on, man, think!
好了  要紧的事不先办
All right, first things fuckin' last.
钻石在谁手上? 求求你们至少帮我一个小忙
Who's got the stones? Please, somebody tell me one little fuckin' favor.
在我手上  我装在袋子里 藏起来了  我怕这边是警察局
I got a bag. Okay? I stashed it 'til we could be sure this place wasn't a police station.
做得好  我们去拿
Good for you. Now let's go get it.
不过先把外面的车子处理掉 外面看起来像旧车拍卖场
First we gotta get rid of those cars. It looks like Sam's Hot Car Lot outside.
金发  留在这里照顾这两个人
Okay. Blondie, stay here and baby-sit them two.
白色和粉红 一人开一辆车  我跟你们走
White and Pink, take a car each. I'll follow you.
你们把车丢了  去拿钻石
You ditch 'em. Pick up the stones.
在跟你们的同时 我会给我们的朋友安排医生
While I'm followin' you, I'll arrange some sort of a doctor for our friend.
不能让这两个人跟他一起
You can't leave these guys here with him.
- 为什么不行? - 因为他是神经病
- Why not? - Because he's a fuckin' psycho.
如果你认为乔火大 那跟我气他比起来不算什么
And if you think Joe's pissed off...
that ain't nothin' compared to how pissed off I am at him...
让我跟那畜牲在同一个房间
for puttin' me in the same room as that bastard.
你看到我多忍气吞声了吧  艾迪?
You see what I've been puttin' up with, Eddie?
我走进来  叫这些人留在原地
I fuckin' walked in here, I told these guys about stayin' put.
白色先生突然掏枪指著我的脸 骂我王八蛋  说要把我干掉
Mr. White whips out his gun, he's stickin' it in my face...
callin' me a motherfucker, sayin' he's gonna blow me away...
唧唧歪歪，唧唧歪歪
and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
就是他害那边变成疯狂射击场
He's the reason the joint turned into a shootin' spree.
你是什么? 哑巴夥伴? 告诉他
What are you, a fuckin' silent partner? Tell him!
他在店里发狂  现在似乎好了
He went crazy in the store, but he seems all right now.
他当时是这样做的  砰...
This is what he was doin': bam, bam...
对  砰...
bam, bam. Yeah, bam, bam, bam, bam, bam.
我说别碰警报器  他们偏要
I told 'em not to touch the fuckin' alarm, they did.
他们要是没做我说别做的事 他们会还活著
If they hadn't have done what I told 'em not to do, they'd still be alive.
我的大英雄
My fuckin' hero.
谢谢
Thanks.
那是你乱开杀戒的藉口吗?
That's your excuse for going on a kill-crazy rampage?
我不喜欢警报  白色先生
I don't like alarms, Mr. White.
谁看著警察有关系吗?
What does it matter who stays with the cop?
他看过所有人  不能放他走的
We ain't lettin' him go. He's seen everybody.
我从来没看过你们
I haven't been looking at you guys.
闭上狗嘴
Shut the fuck up, man!
你们当初不该把他带出来的
You guys should never have taken him outta the trunk in the first place.
我们想查设计的事他知道多少
We tried to find out about the setup.
没有设计这回事
There is no fuckin' setup!
以下是通知
Now here's the news!
金发  你留下来照顾这两个
Blondie, you stay here, take care of these two!
白色和粉红跟我走
White and Pink, you come with me,
乔要是看到这么多车停在外面
'cause if Joe gets here...and he sees all these cars parked outside...
他会像气你们一样的气我
I swear to you he's gonna be just as mad at me as he is at you.
好  走吧
Fine. Let's go.
终於就剩我们了
Alone at last.
你猜怎么著?
Guess what.
我想我停在红线区
I think I'm parked in the red zone.
我们说到哪里了?
Now, where were we?
我跟你说过  我不知道设计的事
I told you, I don't know anything about any fuckin' setup.
我投入警界才八个月 他们什么都没告诉我
I've been on the force for only eight months. They don't tell me anything.
没人告诉我  想折磨我就来吧
Nobody tells me shit. You can torture me all you want.
折磨你? 那倒是个好主意 我喜欢  对
Torture you? That's a good...That's a good idea. I like that one, yeah.
连你的老板都说没人设计你们
Even your boss said there wasn't a setup.
我的什么?
My what?
你的老板
Your boss.
对不起  朋友
Excuse me, pal.
有件事我想跟你说清楚 我没有老板
One thing I wanna make clear to you: I don't have a boss.
没有人能支使我做事
Nobody tells me what to do.
明白吗?
You understand?
你听到我说的吗  狗娘养的?
You hear what I said, you son of a bitch?
好...你没有老板  好...
All right, all right, all right, you don't have a boss.
把这鬼东西擦掉
Get that fuckin' shit off.
听著  我不会耍你  好吗?
Look, I'm not gonna bullshit you, okay?
我不管你知道或不知道什么
I don't really give a good fuck what you know or don't know...
反正我就是要折磨你
but I'm gonna torture you anyway...
不管怎么样
regardless.
得不到消息
Not to get information.
折磨条子逗我开心
It's amusing to me...to torture a cop.
爱说什么随你  我全听过了
You can say anything you want because I've heard it all before.
你能做的只是祈求赶快死去
All you can do is...pray for a quick death...
你无法如愿的
which...you ain't gonna get.
天哪
Oh, God.
你听过K比利的 "70年代老歌精选"吗?
You ever listen to K-BILLY's "Super Sounds of the '70s"?
我最喜欢的节目
It's my personal favorite.
乔伊根和盖利瑞佛提 组成的"史提勒汽车"二重唱
Joe Egan and Gerry Rafferty were a duo known as Stealer's Wheel
1974年4月录制的这首狄伦式畅销曲
when they recorded this Dylanesque, pop, bubble-gum favorite from April of 1974.
升到第五名
That reached up to number five...
请继续收听K比利的 "70年代老歌精选"
as K-BILLY's "Super Sounds of the '70s" continues.
别动
Hold still.
别动  混蛋
Hold still, you fuck.
对你我都一样好吗?
Was that good for you too?
怎么回事?
Hey, what's goin' on?
你听到没?
You hear that?
别乱跑  我马上回来
Don't go anywhere. I'll be right back.
不要
Don't!
住手...
Stop! Stop!
什么?
What?
怎么了?
What's the matter?
别这么做  求求你不要
Don't do this.
会烧一点点吗?
That burn a little bit?
不要  住手
Don't! Stop!
求求你  住手...跟我说话
Please stop. Just stop. Stop. Just talk to me.
求求你  别烧我  求求你
Don't. Please. Don't burn me, please.
我求你  我不知道你们的事
I don't know anything about any of you fucking guys.
我什么都不会说  不要...
I'm not gonna say anything. No!
不  求求你不要
Please, no.
- 你说完了吗? 你说完了吗? - 住手
- You all through? You all through? - Stop!
求求你  我孩子还小...
Please. I got a little kid at home.
说完了吗?
You all done?
- 不要  不要 - 来点火吧  稻草人...
- Don't! - Have some fire.
妈的
Oh, shit.
嗨
Hey, you.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
马文
Marvin.
马文什么?
Marvin what?
马文奈许
Marvin Nash.
听著  马文  我是...
Listen to me, Marvin. I'm a...
听著  马文  我是警察
Listen to me, Marvin Nash. I'm a cop.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
你知道?
You do?
对  你叫佛瑞狄什么
Yeah. Your name's Freddy somethin'.
纽温戴克
Newendyke.
佛瑞狄纽温戴克
Freddy Newendyke.
法兰克佛薛提
Frankie Ferchetti...
五个月前左右给我们介绍过
introduced us about five months ago.
我根本不记得
I don't remember that at all.
我记得
I do.
佛瑞狄
Freddy.
我看起来怎么样?
How do I look?
干嘛?
What?
我不知道要怎么告诉你  马文
I don't know what to tell you, Marvin.
那王八蛋
That fuck.
那变态的王八蛋
That sick fuck!
那变态的臭王八蛋
That fuckin' bastard!
马文  我　要你撑下去
Marvin, I need you to hold on.
一条街外有警察等著攻进来
There's cops waiting to move a block away.
什么? 他们还在等什么?
What the fuck are they waiting for?
那臭家伙划破我的脸 把我耳朵割下来
This fuckin' guy, he slashes my face and cuts my fuckin' ear off!
我破相了
I'm fuckin' deformed!
操你妈
Fuck you!
操你妈  我就快死在这里 我快死了
I'm fuckin' dyin' here! I'm fuckin' dyin'!
乔出现之前他们不会露面
They're not to make a move 'til Joe Cabot shows up.
我被派来抓他的
I was sent in to get him.
你听到了  他们说他在路上
All right? You heard 'em. They said he's on his way.
别胆怯了
Don't pussy out on me now, Marvin.
我们要坐在这里流血
We're just gonna sit here and bleed...
直到乔的头探进那扇门为止
'til Joe Cabot sticks his fuckin' head through that door.
向里面的混蛋问好
Say hello to a motherfucker who's inside.
卡伯要打劫了 猜猜看他要谁加入?
Cabot's doing a job. He wants me on the team.
这最好不是佛瑞狄式的笑话
This better not be a joke.
这不是笑话 我在里面参上一脚了
This ain't a joke. I'm in. I'm up his ass.
好人艾迪告诉我乔想见我
Nice Guy Eddie tells me Joe wants to meet me.
他说我应该在家等电话
He says I should just wait for a phone call.
在电话旁等了三天之後 他昨晚打来说"乔准备好了"
After waiting three days he calls me last night and says Joe's ready.
他15分钟内来接我
He'll pick me up in 15 minutes.
- 谁去接你? - 好人  我们到酒吧去
- Who picked you up? - Nice Guy. We get to a bar.
- 什么酒吧? - 盖狄纳的"冒烟彼得"
- What bar? - Smokey Pete's in Gardena.
我们到那边
We get there...
我跟乔和白色先生碰面  那是假名  我是橘色先生
and I meet Joe and a guy named Mr. White. Phony name. My name's Mr. Orange.
橘色先生?
Mr. Orange?
橘色先生
Mr. Orange.
好  橘色先生
Okay, Mr. Orange.
- 以前看过这小子吗? - 谁? 白色先生吗?
- You ever see this motherfucker before? - Who? Mr. White?
是的  白色先生
Yes. Mr. White.
不熟悉
No.
他不是卡伯的手下之一  一定是外地来的
He ain't one of Cabot's men either. He's gotta be from out of town.
乔跟他很熟
Joe knows him good.
你怎么看得出来?
How can you tell?
他们跟对方谈话的样子 看得出来他们是兄弟
The way they talk. You can tell they're buddies.
你们谈过话吗?
You two talk?
谁? 我跟乔?
Me and Joe?
白色先生
Mr. White.
- 一点点 - 谈什么?
- A little. - About what?
- 酿酒人 - 密尔瓦基酿酒人队
- The Brewers. - Milwaukee Brewers?
对  显然他们前天晚上打赢了 他赌他们赢赚一笔
They won the night before. He made some money off them.
太棒了 如果他是酿酒人的球迷 他一定是威斯康辛州来的
Good. If this crook's a Brewers fan, he's gotta be from Wisconsin.
我敢跟你赌我这条老命 密尔瓦基有这位白色先生的案底
And I'll bet you everything they got a sheet in Milwaukee on this Mr. White's ass.
所以我要你看一下在密尔瓦基 有持枪抢劫案底的人的脸
So I want you to go through everybody in Milwaukee...
帮这张脸找个名字
with a history of armed robbery and put a name to the face.
做得好  佛瑞狄
Nice work, Freddy.
谢谢  老兄
Thank you, my man.
- "长堤麦克"的介绍怎么样? - 好正点
- How was Long Beach Mike's referral? - Perfect.
他给我的支援帮助很大
His backing me up went a long way.
我告诉他们我跟长堤麦克打牌 好人打电话向他确认
I told them I played poker with him. Nice Guy checked it out and said it was A-okay.
他说我没问题  我是好贼 我没有惊慌
Said I was a good thief, I didn't rattle...
我准备行动了
and that I was ready to move.
对他好点  他是好人 如果不是他  我就进不去
He's a good guy. I wouldn't be inside without him.
不  长堤麦克不是你的朋友 长堤麦克是人渣
Long Beach Mike is not your friend. Long Beach Mike is a fucking scumbag.
他出卖他的朋友 他就是那么坏的人  对吧?
He's selling out his friends. That's how nice he fuckin' is.
我会对付这臭王八蛋 你别再想那个人渣
I'll take care of his ass...but you get that scumbag out of mind
应付正事  听到吗?
and take care of business.
没了
Gone.
你用过"厕所故事"吗?
Use the commode story?
什么是厕所故事?
What's the commode story?
那是一个场景  背熟它
It's a scene. Memorize it.
- 什么? - 卧底警察必须是马龙白兰度
- A what? - Undercover cops gotta be Brando.
要做这工作 你必须是伟大的演员  演技要自然
To do this job you gotta be a great actor, naturalistic.
你必须要非常自然
You gotta be naturalistic as hell.
因为你不是好演员就是坏演员 差劲的演技干这行没有鸟用
If you're a bad actor, that's bullshit in this job.
这是什么?
What is this?
毒品交易的趣闻
That's an amusing anecdote about a drug deal.
交易时会碰到的好笑的事
Something funny that happened to you while you were doing a job.
我得记住这么多?
I gotta memorize all this?
这玩意超出四页耶
There's four pages of this shit.
就把它想成一个笑话  好吗?
Think about it like it's a joke.
记住重要的  其它的自己编
Memorize what's important. The rest you make your own.
你会说笑话吧?
You can tell a joke, can't you?
不会
No.
Well, pretend you're Don Rickles and tell a joke, all right?
假想你是唐里柯说笑话  好吗?
The things you gotta remember are the details. The details sell your story.
你要记住的是细节 因为细节才能推销你的故事
This particular story takes place in a men's room.
这个特别的故事发生在男厕内
You gotta know all the details...
所以你要知道男厕的细节
whether they got paper towels or a blower to dry your hands.
要知道有没有纸巾或烘手机
You gotta know if the stalls ain't got no doors or not.
要知道每一间厕所有没有门
You gotta know if they got liquid soap or that pink, granulated shit...
要知道有没有清洁乳
they used in high school.
高中生用的那种粉红色颗粒
You gotta know if they got hot water or not, if it stinks...
要知道有没有热水  厕所臭不臭
if some nasty, lowlife, scum-ridden motherfucker...sprayed diarrhea all over one of the bowls.
有没有脏鬼拉肚子  喷得到处都是
You gotta know every detail there is to know about this commode.
你要知道这间厕所里的所有细节
What you gotta do is take all them details and make 'em your own.
要记下这些细节  变成你自己的
While you're doing that, remember that this story is about you...
同时记住这是你的故事
and how you perceived the events that went down.
你如何留意所发生的事件
The only way to do that is keep sayin' it and sayin' it and sayin' it.
唯一的方法就是不停的说...
This is during the L.A. marijuana drought, 1986.
1986年洛杉矶闹大麻荒
I still had a connection, which was insane 'cause...
我还有贩毒关系  太疯狂了
you couldn't get any weed anywhere then.
因为当时到哪里都买不到大麻
Anyway, I had a connection with this hippie chick in Santa Cruz
总之  我跟圣库鲁兹一个嬉皮妞买
and all my friends knew it. They call me and say, "Hey, Freddy..."
我朋友都知道  他们打电话给我说 "嘿  佛瑞狄"
I say, "Hey, dude. You gettin' some?
"嘿  小子  你有货吗? "
Can you get some for me too?"
"你可以也帮我弄一点吗? "
They knew I still smoked, so they asked me to buy some for them.
他们知道我还有在吸 叫我买的时候顺便帮他们带
It got to be...
可是一定要  要...
Every time I bought some weed I was buyin' for four or five people.
我每次都帮四五个不同的人买
Finally I said, fuck this shit. I'm makin' this bitch rich.
终於我说了  老子不干了  我在让这个婊子赚钱 她却坐享其成
She didn't even have to meet these people. I was doing all the work.
她甚至不用跟这些人打交道 都是我在办事
That got to be a pain in the ass, people calling all the time.
那真的是很烦 老是有人打电话给我
I couldn't even rent a tape without six fuckin' interruptions.
连看录影带都被六通电话打断
"When's the next time you're gettin' some?"
"你下次什么时候买货? "
"Motherfucker, I'm tryin' to watch The Lost Boys.
"混蛋  我正在看《粗野少年族》
When I get some, I'll call you."
等弄到手  我会打给你"
Then these rink-a-dink potheads come by.
後来有三个瘾君子来找我
They're my friends and everything, but still...
他们是我的朋友  不过还是...
I got it laid out in 60-dollar bags,
我把大麻装成60块一袋
they don't want 60 dollars worth.
他们不要60块的
They want ten dollars' worth,
要10块的
and breaking it up wasn't easy.
把大麻分成烦人的小袋装
I don't even know what ten dollars' worth looks like.
我不知道10块一袋是什么样子
This was a very weird situation.
那是很奇怪的局面
Remember back in '86...there was a major fuckin' drought.
不知道你们记不记得68年 那时候大麻荒闹得好凶
Nobody had anything.
没有人有任何货
People were livin' on resin, smokin' the wood in their pipes.
大家靠树脂维生 用烟斗抽了好几个月木头
This chick had a bunch
这个妞有一大堆货
and she's beggin' me to sell it.
她哀求我去卖
So I told her I wasn't gonna be Joe the pot man anymore...
我告诉她 我已经不再做毒贩了
but I would take a little bit and sell it to my close friends.
但是我会拿一点卖给最熟的朋友
She agreed and we kept the same arrangement as before...
她同意  我们维持以前的协议
ten percent and free pot for me...
抽一成  我的大麻免费
if I helped her that weekend.
只要我那个周末帮她忙
She was sellin' a brick of weed and didn't wanna go to the buy alone.
她有一堆大麻卖不出去 她不想自己去交易
Her brother usually goes with her,
有个黑人兄弟通常会陪她去
- but he's in County unexpectedly. - What for?
- 但他出乎意料被关在牢里 - 什么罪名?
His traffic tickets gone to warrant. They stopped him,
他交通罚单没缴变拘票 警方因某种理由拦下他
found warrants on him, took him to County.
发现他身上有拘票  抓进牢里
She doesn't wanna walk around alone with all that weed.
她不想带著大麻乱跑
I don't wanna do this. I have a very bad feeling about it.
可是我不想这么做 我有不太妙的预感
She keeps asking me, asking me.
可是她一直要求我...
Finally I said okay 'cause I'm sick of hearing it.
我终於说好  因为我听腻了
- So we go to the train station...
我们要在车站接一个人
Wait. You're goin' to the train station with the weed on ya?
等一下 你们带大麻到车站接买主?
The guy needed it right away.
他马上就要  别问我为什么
Anyway,we get to the train station and we're waitin' for the guy.
总之  我们到车站等买主
I'm carryin' the weed in a carry-on bag. I gotta take a piss,
我把大麻装在手提袋里带著走 我要撤尿
so I tell her I'm goin' to the boy's room.
所以我跟她说马上回来 我要去男厕
So I walk into the men's room and who's standing there?
我走进男厕  谁站在那边?
Four Los Angeles County sheriffs and a German shepherd.
四个洛杉矶警官和一支狼犬
They're waitin' for you?
他们在等你?
No, they're just talkin'.
不  只是一群条子在男厕聊天
When I walked in, they all stopped talkin' and they looked at me.
我走进门的时候 他们停下在谈的事看著我
That's hard. That's a fuckin' hard situation.
难啊  那是很棘手的场面
German shepherd starts barking.
狼犬开始吠
He's barkin' at me.
它在对我吠
I mean, it's obvious he's barkin' at me.
它显然是在对我吠
Every nerve ending, all of my senses, the blood in the veins was screamin':
每条神经  我的意识  血液 都在尖叫:
"Take off, man. Just bail. Get the fuck outta there."
"跑啊  翘头  快闪"
Panic hits me like a bucket of water.
惊慌像一桶水似地泼向我 泼到我脸上
Bam! Right in the face.
我站在那边  沈浸在惊慌中
I'm drenched in panic and these cops are lookin' at me and they know it.
那些警察都看著我
They can smell it, sure as that fuckin' dog can.
他们知道  他们察觉得到 就像那条狗一样
They can smell it on me.
他们察觉到我有大麻
Shut up.
住口
So anyway, I got my gun drawn.
我把枪拔了出来
I point it at this guy
指著这个人
and I tell him: "Freeze. Don't fuckin' move."
我跟他说"别动  别乱动"
This little idiot's looking right at me and saying
这小白痴盯著我看 点头说好  他说
"I know, I know."
"我知道..."
But meanwhile his right hand is creepin' toward the glove box.
右手却慢慢摸向置物箱
I scream at him, "Asshole!
我跟他大吼说"混蛋"
I'm gonna blow you away right now! Put your hands on the dash."
"我会杀死你  手放在丁表板上"
He's still looking at me, nodding his head.
他还是看著我 点头说
"I know, buddy, I know."
"我知道  我知道..."
Meanwhile his hand is still going for the glove box.
但他的手还是摸向置物箱
And I said...
我说
"Buddy, I'm gonna shoot you in the face...
我说"我要开枪打你的脸了
if you don't put your hands up."
要是你不把手放在丁表板上"
Then this guy's girlfriend, this real sexy Oriental bitch...
然後这个人的女朋友 很性感的东方马子
she starts screaming at him: "Chuck, what are you doin'?
她开始喊他"恰克  你干嘛?
Listen to the officer! Put your hands on the dash!"
听警官的话  把手放在丁表板上"
So then the guy snaps out of it
然後没事似的  他突然觉醒
and puts his hands on the dash.
漫不经心地把手放在丁表板上
- What was he goin' for? - His fucking registration.
- 他要拿什么? - 他的行照
- You're kidding. - No, man!
你在开玩笑
Stupid citizen doesn't know how close he came to gettin' blown away.
不  这蠢材不知道他差点没命
That close, man.
就差那么一点点
You knew how to handle that situation.
你知道怎么应付那个场面
You shit your pants, dive in and swim.
在裤子里撤尿  跳进去游泳
- Tell me more about Cabot. - I don't know.
- 多跟我说一些卡伯的事 - 我不知道
He's a cool guy.
他是很绘的人
He's funny. He's a funny guy.
他很有趣  是个有趣的人
You remember the Fantastic Four?
记得"四超人"吗?
Yeah, with that invisible bitch and "Flame on" and shit, right?
嗯  他们有"隐形女"和"火焰人"
Thing.
他是"石怪"
Motherfucker...Iooks just like the Thing.
这家伙看起来就像"石怪"
Hey! Showtime!
好戏上场罗
- Grab your jacket. I'm parked outside. - I'll be right down.
- 穿上外套  我停在外面 - 马上下来
He'll be right down.
他马上下来
Don't pussy out on me now.
你可别临阵脚软
They don't know.
他们不知道
They don't know shit.
他们什么都不知道
You're not gonna get hurt.
你不会有三长两短
You're fuckin' Baretta.
你是硬汉
They believe every fuckin' word 'cause you're super cool.
他们相信每一句话 因为你太酷了
There goes our boy.
我们的人出来了
The guy has to have rocks in his head the size of Gibraltar to work undercover.
我发誓 这家伙脑袋有毛病才会去干卧底
- You want one of these? - Yeah, give me the bear claw.
- 你要吗? - 好  给我熊爪
I know what I'm talking about.
我知道我在说什么  好吗?
Black women ain't the same as white women.
黑妞跟白妞不一样
There's a slight difference.
有些许的差别
Very funny. You know what I mean.
很好笑  你知道我的意思
What a white bitch will put up with, a black bitch wouldn't for a minute.
白妞比黑妞更能容忍
If you cross their line, they fuck you up.
她们是有界限  要是越了界 她们就修理你
I gotta go along with Pink on that.
我同意粉红先生说的  我看过
Okay, Mr. Expert, if this is such a truism...
专家先生  假如这是事实
why is it that every nigger I know treats his woman like a piece of shit?
为何我认识的黑人都糟蹋他的女人?
I'll bet those same niggers
我跟你打赌那些是同样的黑人
who show their ass in public...
爱在公开场合炫耀的
when their bitches get 'em home they chill the fuck out.
等他们的女人把他们揪回家 他们就冷静下来了
- Not these guys. - Oh, yeah. Those guys too.
- 这些人可不会 - 对  这些人也是
Tell you guys a story.
跟你们说一个故事
In one of Daddy's clubs there's a black cocktail waitress named Elois.
在我爸的一家俱乐部里 有个叫伊洛丝的黑人女服务生
Elois?
伊洛丝?
Yeah, Elois.
伊洛丝...
E and Lois. We called her Lady E.
我们叫她伊小姐
Where was she from? Compton?
她从哪里来的? 康普顿吗?
She's from Ladora Heights.
她从勒多拉高地来的
Ladora Heights. The black Beverly Hills.
勒多拉高地  黑人比佛利山
It's not the black Beverly Hills. It's the black Palos Verdes.
不  不是黑人比佛利山 是"黑人的帕洛斯佛狄斯"
Anyway...Lady E,
不管啦  伊小姐
she was a man-eater-upper. Un-fuckin'-believable.
她是一个"男人兴奋剂" 他妈的令人难以相信
Every guy who ever saw her had to jack off to her at least once.
看过她的男人起码要打一次手枪
You know who she looked like? Christie Love.
知道她长得像谁吗? 克丽丝蒂宝贝
Remember that TV show Get Christie Love...
记得那个电视节目吗?
about the black female cop? She always used to say,
讲一个黑人女警察  她老说...
"You're under arrest, sugar! "
"你被捕了  甜心"
Who played Christie Love?
演克丽丝蒂宝贝的妞叫什么?
Pam Grier.
潘古莱尔
No, it wasn't Pam Grier. Pam Grier was the other one.
不  不是潘古莱尔 潘古莱尔是另一个
Pam Grier did the film.
潘古莱尔演的是电影
Christie Love was like a Pam Grier TV show without Pam Grier.
克丽丝蒂宝贝是电视剧
- So, who was Christie Love? - How should I know?
- 那么  谁是克丽丝蒂宝贝? - 我怎么知道?
Great. Now I'm totally fuckin' tortured.
好极了  现在我完全不解了
Whoever it was, she looked exactly like Elois.
不管是谁  那不重要 她看起来像极了伊洛丝
- Anne Francis. - No. That was Honey West.
- 安法兰西斯 - 不  那是"哈妮威斯特"
Anne Francis is white.
安法兰西斯是白人
I'm tryin' to tell a story here.
闭嘴  我在说故事
She looked exactly like Elois.
她看起来和伊洛丝一模一样
We come into the club one night...
总之  有天晚上我到俱乐部
and there's Carlos, the bartender.
卡洛斯在  他是酒保
He's a wetback. He's a friend of mine.
非法墨西哥工人  是我的朋友
I says to him, "Carlos, where's Lady E tonight?"
我问他  今晚伊小姐在哪里?
Apparently Lady E was married to real piece of dog shit, a real animal.
伊小姐显然嫁给一个超级混蛋 我是说  真正的禽兽
He used to do things to her.
他常对她做一些事
Like what? What would he do?
做事? 比方? 他会做什么?
Beat her up?
他揍她还是干嘛?
I don't know. He just did things.
我不知道他做什么 他就是会做一些事  好不好?
So anyway, one night she plays it real cool.
总之  有天晚上她冷静行事
She waits for him to get drunk.
她等这王八羔子喝醉
He falls asleep on the fuckin' couch.
他在沙发上睡著了 她偷偷走向他
She sneaks up on him, puts some glue on his dick...
在他老二上倒超强黏胶
and glues his dick to his belly.
把他的老二黏在肚皮上
Jesus Christ!
- 少来 - 天啊
I'm serious, man. I'm dead serious.
我说真的  真的  绝对真的
They had to call the paramedics to cut the prick loose.
他们叫医疗人员来把老二切开
Was he all pissed off?
他有没有很火大?
How would you feel if you
你觉得会怎么样?
...had to do a fuckin' handstand to take a piss?
如果每次小便都要倒立
You guys like to tell jokes and giggle and kid around, huh?
你们爱说笑话  胡闹  玩耍?
Giggling like a bunch of girls in the schoolyard.
像一群校园里的小妞
Well, let me tell a joke.
让我跟你们说个笑话
Five guys sittin' in a bullpen San Quentin...
五个人蹲在圣昆丁的牢里
wonderin' how the fuck they got there.
纳闷他们怎么会沦落到那边
"What did we do wrong? What shouldn't we have done?
我们做错什么? 本该怎么做?
It's your fault, his fault..."
我们没做什么  等等的 是你的错  我的错  他的错
All that bullshit.
那一类的鬼扯淡
Finally somebody says..."Wait a minute.
终於有人想出来了  等一下
While we were planning this caper we just sat around tellin' fuckin' jokes."
在计划这次抢劫时 我们做的只是坐著讲笑话
Got the message?
了解没有?
I don't mean to holler at ya.
我没有要骂你们的意思
When this caper's over, and I'm sure it'll be successful...
等这次抢劫结束了 我相信一定是很成功的一票
we'll go down to Hawaiian lslands, I'll laugh with all of youse.
我们去夏威夷  我陪你们闹
Find me a different character down there.
到那边你们会发现我变了个人
Right now it's a matter of business.
现在  这可是正经事
With the exception of Eddie and myself who you already know...
除了艾迪和我自己之外 你们已经认识我们了
we're gonna be using aliases on this job.
这次抢劫我们要用化名
Under no circumstances do we want any one of you to relate to each other by your Christian names.
不论在任何情况下 你们不得以本名彼此交谈
And I don't want any talk about yourself personally.
我不希望任何人谈私人的事
That includes where you been, your wife's name where you might've done time...
包括去过哪里  老婆的名字 可能在哪里服过刑
or a bank maybe you robbed in St. Petersburg.
或是在匹兹堡街抢过的怠行
All I want you guys to talk about, if you have to...
我只要你们谈... 如果非谈不可
is what you're gonna do. That should do it.
你们要做什么  这样应该行了
These are your names...
以下是你们的名字
Mr. Brown,
棕色先生
Mr. White...
白色先生
Mr. Blonde,
金发先生
Mr. Blue...
蓝色先生
Mr. Orange
橘色先生
and Mr. Pink.
粉红先生
Why am I Mr. Pink?
为什么我是粉红先生?
Because you're a faggot! All right?
因为你是同性恋  行不行?
Why can't we pick our own colors?
为什么不能自己挑颜色?
No way. No way. Tried it once. It doesn't work.
不成...试过一次  行不通
You get four guys all fightin' over who gets to be Mr. Black.
四个人都抢著要当黑色先生
They don't know each other, so nobody wants to back down.
他们彼此不认识 所以没有人肯让步
No way. I pick. You're Mr. Pink. Be thankful you're not Mr. Yellow.
不行  我挑  你是粉红先生 要庆幸你不是黄色先生
But Mr. Brown, that's too close to Mr. Shit.
好  但棕色先生太像狗屎先生
Mr. Pink sounds like Mr. Pussy.
粉红先生听起来像娘娘腔先生
How about Mr. Purple? That's sounds good.
紫色先生怎么样? 听起来挺好的
I'll be Mr. Purple.
我可以做紫色先生
You're not Mr. Purple.
你不是紫色先生
Some guy on some other job is Mr. Purple. You're Mr. Pink!
另外一票有个人是紫色先生 你是粉红先生
Who cares what your name is?
谁在乎你叫什么名字
Easy for you to say. You're Mr. White. You have a cool-sounding name.
是  你说起来倒容易 你是白色先生  听起来很正点
If it's no big deal to be Mr. Pink, you wanna trade?
要是当粉红先生没啥大不了 你要交换吗?
Nobody's tradin' with anybody.
谁也不准交换
This ain't a goddamn fuckin' city council meeting, you know.
这又不是在开市议会
Now listen up, Mr. Pink.
听著  粉红先生
There's two ways you can go on this job...
干这票买卖你只有两条路走
my way or the highway. What's it gonna be, Mr. Pink?
我的路  或是离开 要哪一条  粉红先生?
Jesus Christ, Joe. Fuckin' forget about it.
老天  乔  算了吧
It's beneath me.
我犯不著这样
I'm Mr. Pink. Let's move on.
我是粉红先生了  继续吧
I'll move on when I feel like it.
我想继续就会继续
Do all you guys got the goddamn message?
你们了解没有?
I'm so goddamn mad hollerin' at you guys, I can hardly talk.
你们气死我了  对你们吼叫 我都快不能讲话了
Let's go to work.
咱们办事吧
Let's go over it. Where are you?
我们来顺一遍  你在哪里?
I stand outside and guard the door. I don't let anybody go in or out.
我站在外面守门  不让任何人进出
- Mr. Brown. - He waits in the car.
- 棕色先生 - 棕色先生在车里等
I give him the signal, he pulls up in front.
车停在对街 等我打信号  他就停到店门口
- Mr. Blonde and Mr. Blue. - Crowd control.
- 金发先生和蓝色先生 - 控制人群
They handle the customers and the employees.
他们应付顾客和店员
That girl's ass.
那个女孩的屁股怎么办?
Sittin' right here on my dick.
坐在我老二上
Myself and Mr. Pink?
我和粉红先生
You two take the manager and make him give you the diamonds.
你们负责经理  让他交出钻石
We're there for those stones, period.
我们在场负责那些钻石
Since no display cases are being fucked with, no alarms should go off.
只要没有展示箱被乱碰到 应该没有警报器会响
We're out in two minutes, not one second longer.
我们在整整两分钟内离开
What if the manager won't give you the diamonds?
万一经理不交钻石怎么办?
A store like this is insured up the ass.
在对付这种店的时候 他们投保了各式各样的保险
They're not supposed to give you any resistance whatsoever.
他们不应该会做任何抵抗
If you get a customer or an employee who thinks he's Charles Bronson...
要是碰到有顾客或员工 自以为是查理士布朗逊
smash their nose with your gun. Drops him right to the floor.
拿起枪柄  打烂他们的鼻子 把他们摔在地上
Everyone jumps.
大家跳起来
He falls down screaming, blood squirts out of his nose.
他倒下尖叫  血从鼻子迸出来
Freaks everybody out. Nobody says fuckin' shit after that.
吓坏每个人  之後没人敢吭声
Some bitch might talk shit to you.
你可能会碰到骂你的女人
Give her a look like she's next. Watch her shut the fuck up.
瞪她一眼  好像下一个就要揍她 确定她把嘴巴闭起来
If it's the manager, that's different.
对付经理则是另一种做法
The managers know not to fuck around so if he's giving you static...
经理很清楚不可以胡来 所以要是碰到跟你顶嘴的
he probably thinks he's a real cowboy so you gotta that bastard in two.
他或许自以为是真的牛仔 你得把那个混蛋劈成两半
If he won't tell ya something, cut off one of his fingers.
你如果想知道什么  他不肯说 把他的指头切一根下来
The little one.
小指
Then tell him his thumb's next. After that he'll tell you if he wears ladies underwear.
然後告诉他下一个是姆指 之後他会说有没有穿女人内裤
I'm hungry. Let's get a taco.
我饿了  我们去买墨西哥
Fuck.
操
Jesus. I'm blind, man.
老天  我瞎了
I'm fuckin' blind.
我他妈的瞎了
No, you just got blood in your eyes.
你没瞎  只是眼睛沾到血
Is he dead?
他死了吗?
Did he die or not?
他到底是不是死了?
Let's go.
走
Hold it! Get out!
等等  等等  那边
Get out of the fuckin' car!
下车
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Larry.
对不起  对不起  赖利
I can't believe she killed me. Who'd have fucking thought that?
我不敢相信她会杀我 谁会想得到呢?
Hey, just cancel that shit right now.
别再胡说了
You're hurt. You're hurt real fuckin' bad.
你受伤了  你伤得很重
But you ain't dying.
可是你不会死
All this blood's scaring the shit out of me, Larry.
这些血吓坏我了  赖利
I'm gonna die. I know it.
我要死了  我知道
What the fuck happened?
出了什么事?
He slashed the cop's face, cut off his ear and was gonna burn him alive.
他割条子的脸 切下他的耳朵  还要把他活活烧死
What? I didn't hear you.
什么? 我没听到你说的
I said...
我说...
Blonde went crazy.
金发发疯了
He slashed the cop's face, cut off his ear and was gonna burn him alive.
他割条子的脸 切下他的耳朵  还要把他活活烧死
This cop?
这个条子?
He went crazy? Something like that?
他发疯了  那一类的吗?
Worse or better?
更严重或更好?
Eddie, he was pulling a burn, man.
艾迪  他要放火啊
He was gonna kill the cop and me.
他要杀了条子和我
When you guys walked in, he was gonna kill you and run with the diamonds.
你们一走出门 他本来要杀了你们带钻石逃走
What'd I tell ya?
我怎么跟你说的?
That sick piece of shit was a stone-cold psycho.
那个变态狂是神经病
You should've asked the cop, not just killed him.
你可以问条子  如果你没杀他
He talked about what he was gonna do when he was slicing him up.
他在割他的脸时说出计划
I don't buy it.
我不相信
Doesn't make sense.
这没有道理
Makes perfect fuckin' sense to me.
我的计划非常成熟
You didn't see how he acted during the job. We did.
你没看到他在行动时的表现  我们看到了
He's right. The ear's hacked off.
他没错  是割掉一只耳朵
Let me just say this out loud, 'cause I wanna get this straight.
让我再大声的说一遍，因为我想弄明白真相
You're saying that Mr. Blonde...
你说金发先生
was gonna kill you...
要杀你
and then when we got back he was gonna kill us...
而当我们回来后  他还要杀了我们...
take the diamonds and scram.
夺走钻石
I'm right about that, right? That's your story?
你的意思是这样吧?
I swear on my mother's soul...
我以母亲的名义发誓...
that's what happened.
真的是这样
The man you killed just got released from prison.
你杀的那个人刚刚才从监狱出来
He got caught at a company warehouse full of hot items.
在一间满是违禁品的公司仓库里被捕
He could've fuckin' walked.
他可以洗脱罪名
All he had to do was say my dad's name, but he didn't; he kept his mouth shut.
只要他说出我父亲的名字  但他没有  他守口如瓶
He did his fuckin' time like a man.
他真的是硬汉
He did four years for us.
为我们做了四年牢
So, Mr. Orange...
那么  橘色先生...
you're telling me that this good friend of mine...
你告诉我  我的这位好朋友...
who did four years for my father...
为我父亲做了四年牢...
who, in four years, never made a deal, no matter what they offered him...
从没有与警方妥协  没向他们说出半个字的人...
you're telling me that now that he's free...
你告诉我他现在自由了...
and we're making good on our commitment to him...
而我们已经向他做了很好的许诺...
he's just gonna decide, out of the fucking blue...
他却决定把我们都干掉
to rip us off?
除了那个警察?
Why don't you tell me what really happened.
为什么你不告诉我真正发生了些什么
What the hell for?
出了什么事?
It'd just be more bullshit.
不要再废话了
This man set us up.
这个人陷害我们
Dad, I'm sorry, but I don't know what's happening.
老爸  对不起  我不知道究竟发生了什么
- It's all right. I do. - What are you talking about?
- 没关系  我知道 - 你在说些什么?
That lump of shit's workin' with the L.A.P.D.
那个蠢货是警方派来的
I don't have the slightest fucking idea...
我真搞不懂...
what you're talking about.
你究竟在说些什么
Joe, I don't know what you think you know, but you're wrong.
乔  我不知道你认为自己知道了什么  但你错了
Like hell I am.
我吗
Trust me on this. You've made a mistake.
请相信我  你错了
He's a good kid.
他是好人
I understand you're super-fuckin'-pissed.
我知道你很火大
We're all real emotional.
我们都很火大
But you're barking up the wrong tree. I know him. He wouldn't do that.
但你弄错了对象  我了解他  他不会做这样的事
You don't know jack shit!
你根本不知道
I do.
我知道
The cocksucker tipped off the cops...
这个杂碎向警方告密...
and got Mr. Brown and Mr. Blue killed.
害了棕色先生和蓝色先生
- Mr. Blue is dead? - Dead as Dillinger.
- 蓝色先生死了? - 死了
How do you know all this?
你怎么知道?
He was the only one I wasn't 100 percent on.
他是我唯一不能相信的人
I should have my head examined, going ahead when I wasn't 100 percent.
我该检讨我自己  在我还没有十足的把握时就开始行动
- That's your proof? - With instinct, you don't need proof.
- 那就是你的证据? - 直觉  是不需要证据的
I ignored it before, but no more.
之前我忽视了  但以后不会
Have you lost your fuckin' mind?
你疯了吗?
I'm not gonna let you make a terrible mistake.
我不会让你犯这个可怕的错误
Come on, guys. Nobody wants this.
别这样  伙计们  没有人想这样的
We're supposed to be fuckin' professionals.
我们该表现得专业些
Larry, look...
赖利  听着
it's been quite a long time.
我们在一起干了很久
A lot of jobs.
做了这么多的事
There's no need for this, man.
这样是完全没必要的  伙计
Let's just put our guns down...
让我们都把枪放下...
and let's settle this...
我们一起商量...
with a fucking conversation.
怎样解决这事
Joe, if you kill that man, you die next.
乔  你要是杀他  你就是下一个
Repeat: you kill him, you die next.
我再说一次: 你杀他  你就是下一个
Larry, we have been friends.
赖利  我们是好朋友
You respect my dad and I respect you...
我尊敬我父亲  我尊敬你...
but I'll put bullets in you.
但我会开枪的
You put that fuckin' gun down now.
马上把枪放下
Goddamn you, Joe...
去你的  乔
don't make me do this.
别逼我
Larry, you stop pointin' that gun at my dad!
赖利  别用枪指着我父亲
I'm sorry, kid.
对不起  伙计
Looks like we're gonna...
看起来我们还可以...
do a little time.
坚持一会儿
I'm a cop.
我是警察
Larry...
赖利...
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm...so sorry.
I'm a cop.
我是个警察
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm...sorr...
Freeze!
别动
Drop the fucking gun, buddy!
放下枪  伙计
- Now! - Put the gun down!
- 马上 - 放下枪
- Don't do it! - Drop the gun, man!
- 不要 - 放下枪
- Drop the fucking gun! - We're gonna blow you away!
- 放下枪 - 我们可要开枪了!